Every week developers release powerful
open-source GitHub projects that help
teams build faster and work smarter. In
this weekly update, we cover top
trending open-source GitHub projects
this week, so you can quickly discover
useful developer tools, AI workflows,
and productivity systems. Without
wasting time, let's get started.
>> Welcome back to Manu AI tutorials. Here,
we explore the exciting world of AI,
latest AI tools for you, so don't forget
to hit that subscribe button and the
notification bell, so you don't miss out
on the latest AI insights. So, let's
start today's video.
>> Project number one, Agent's View,
monitoring dashboard for AI agent
workflows. Agent's View is an
open-source platform that provides
visibility into AI agent activity
through a structured monitoring
interface. It helps developers inspect
execution flows, track interactions, and
understand how agents use tools and
complete tasks. The system connects to
agent environments and presents
operational data in a centralized view.
It focuses on observability and workflow
analysis. This helps teams manage and
debug agent systems more effectively.
Explore the repository to monitor AI
agents. Project number two, SWC, fast
compiler for JavaScript and TypeScript.
SWC is an open-source compiler written
in Rust that transforms JavaScript and
TypeScript code with a focus on speed.
It provides compilation, bundling, and
code transformation workflows used in
modern web development environments.
Developers integrate it into build
systems, frameworks, and tooling
pipelines. The platform focuses on
performance and compatibility. This
helps teams reduce build times and
improve developer productivity. Explore
the repository to accelerate front-end
builds. Project number three, Cypress,
end-to-end testing framework for web
applications. Cypress is an open-source
testing framework that helps developers
write and run end-to-end tests for web
applications. It executes tests directly
in browser environments and provides
tools for debugging, assertions, and
automation. Developers integrate it into
development and CI workflows to validate
application behavior. The platform
focuses on reliability and developer
experience. This helps teams improve
software quality. Explore the repository
to build testing workflows. Project
number four, Pest, testing framework for
Python projects. Pest is an open-source
Python testing framework that simplifies
writing and running automated tests. It
supports unit tests, functional tests,
fixtures, and plugin-based extensions
through a flexible development workflow.
Developers use it across projects of
different sizes to verify code behavior
and prevent regressions. The framework
focuses on simplicity and extensibility.
This helps teams maintain reliable
Python applications. Explore the
repository to improve testing practices.
So, project number five, Open Notebook,
open-source workspace for notes and
knowledge. Open Notebook is an
open-source application that helps users
capture, organize, and manage notes in a
structured environment. It provides
workflows for documenting ideas, storing
information, and maintaining personal or
collaborative knowledge bases.
Developers and knowledge workers run it
locally to keep control over their data.
The platform focuses on openness and
flexibility. This helps users organize
information more effectively. Explore
the repository to manage notes and
knowledge. Project number six,
Puppeteer, browser automation library
for Chrome and Firefox. Puppeteer is an
open-source browser automation library
that provides a high-level API for
controlling browsers programmatically.
Developers use it to automate testing,
web scraping, page generation, and
browser-based workflows. It runs through
scripts that interact with browser
instances and execute actions on web
pages. The library focuses on reliable
automation and developer productivity.
This helps teams build browser-driven
applications. Explore the repository to
automate web workflows. Project number
seven, Chatwoot, customer support
platform with shared inboxes. Chatwoot
is an open-source customer engagement
platform that helps teams manage
conversations across multiple
communication channels. It provides
shared inboxes, automation features, and
customer interaction workflows through a
unified interface. Organizations deploy
it on their own infrastructure and
connect messaging services, websites,
and support channels. The platform
focuses on customer communication and
operational efficiency. This helps teams
deliver better support experiences.
Explore the repository to manage
customer conversations. Well, project
number eight, Money Printer Turbo,
automated short-form video creation
platform. Money Printer Turbo is an
open-source application that generates
videos from text through an automated
content creation workflow. It combines
scripts, voice generation, media assets,
and rendering processes into a single
pipeline. Developers run it locally and
customize content generation settings
according to their needs. The platform
focuses on reducing manual effort in
video production. This helps users
create videos more efficiently. Explore
the repository to automate video
creation. Project number nine,
Understand Anything, AI learning
assistant for complex topics. Understand
Anything is an open-source educational
platform that helps users learn and
explore complex subjects through
AI-powered explanations. It processes
questions and content, then presents
information in a structured and
accessible format. Developers and
learners use it to break down difficult
concepts across different domains. The
platform focuses on understanding and
knowledge transfer. This helps users
learn more effectively. Explore the
repository to build educational AI
workflows. Project number 10 is Oh My
Pi, toolkit for Raspberry Pi setup and
management. Oh My Pi is an open-source
toolkit that simplifies Raspberry Pi
configuration and maintenance workflows.
It provides automation utilities, setup
helpers, and management tools that make
Pi deployments easier to operate.
Developers run it directly on Raspberry
Pi systems and adapt it to their
environments. The project focuses on
convenience and operational efficiency.
This helps users manage Raspberry Pi
devices more effectively. Explore the
repository to improve pie workflows.
Project number 11, samples diso go,
workflow examples for the temporal go
SDK. Temporal go SDK samples is an open
source collection of example
applications that demonstrate how to
build workflows using the temporal go
SDK. It shows practical patterns for
activities, orchestration, retries, and
long-running processes in distributed
systems. Developers use the examples to
learn temporal concepts and
implementation techniques. The project
focuses on education and workflow
design. This helps teams adopt temporal
more quickly. Explore the repository to
learn workflow development. Project
number 12, Tomodachi drawer, drawing and
creativity tool inspired by Tomodachi
style. Tomodachi drawer is an open
source creative application that helps
users create drawings and
character-based artwork through an
interactive workflow. It provides tools
for generating and editing visual
content in a playful environment.
Developers and artists use it locally to
experiment with character creation and
illustration. The platform focuses on
accessibility and creativity. This helps
users produce custom artwork more
easily. Explore the repository to create
character drawings. Project number 13,
strands shell, terminal environment for
AI agent workflows. Strands shell is an
open source command line environment
designed for working with AI agents
through terminal workflows. It combines
shell interactions, tool execution, and
agent capabilities into a unified
interface. Developers use it to
coordinate tasks, automate operations,
and interact with agent systems from the
command line. The platform focuses on
productivity and agent integration. This
helps teams operate AI workflows more
efficiently. Explore the repository to
use agents from the terminal. Project
number 14, Portless, development tool
for port-free local services. Portless
is an open-source project from Versal
Labs that simplifies access to local
services without requiring manual port
management. It provides workflows that
reduce friction when exposing and
connecting development applications.
Developers integrate into local
environments to streamline service
discovery and connectivity. The platform
focuses on developer experience and
convenience. This helps teams work with
local services more efficiently. Explore
the repository to simplify local
development. Project number 14,
DevSpace, personal workspace for
developer productivity. DevSpace is an
open-source platform that helps
developers organize projects, workflows,
and resources inside a unified
workspace. It provides tools for
managing development activities and
maintaining context across tasks.
Developers use it as a central
environment for productivity and project
coordination. The platform focuses on
workflow organization and efficiency.
This helps teams stay productive across
multiple projects. Explore the
repository to organize development work.
Project number 16, Cabinet, personal
knowledge and document organization
system. Cabinet is an open-source
application for storing, organizing, and
retrieving documents and knowledge
resources. It provides structured
workflows for managing information in a
searchable environment. Users run it
locally to maintain control over
personal or team knowledge bases. The
platform focuses on information
management and accessibility. This helps
users keep important content organized.
Explore the repository to manage
knowledge resources. Project number 17,
Code Mode, library for AI coding
workflow integration. Code Mode library
is an open-source project that provides
tooling and protocols for integrating AI
coding workflows into development
environments. It helps connect language
models, tools, and code execution
systems through a structured interface.
Developers use it to build assistance
and coding experiences that interact
with software projects. The platform
focuses on interoperability and
extensibility. This helps teams create
AI-powered development tools. Explore
the repository to integrate coding
workflows. Project number 18, Raven
framework. Framework for AI agent
development. Raven framework is an
open-source platform for building AI
agents and automation systems. It
provides abstractions for workflows,
tool usage, memory, and execution logic
that developers can combine into custom
applications. The framework runs in
local or hosted environments and
supports extensible agent architectures.
It focuses on structured agent
development. This helps teams create
AI-powered workflows more efficiently.
Explore the repository to build agent
applications. Project number 19, JSON
render. AI-driven UI generation from
structured JSON. JSON render is an
open-source library that turns
structured JSON into interactive user
interfaces. Developers define component
catalogs and actions. Then AI systems
generate JSON that the library renders
into real application interfaces. The
framework acts as a controlled runtime
where generated layouts map to approved
UI components and behaviors. It focuses
on predictable AI-driven interface
creation. This helps teams build dynamic
AI-powered applications. Explore the
repository to generate interfaces from
JSON. Project number 20, MacPacker.
Packaging tool for macOS applications.
MacPacker is an open-source utility that
helps developers package and distribute
macOS applications through streamlined
workflows. It automates parts of the
packaging process and prepares
applications for deployment and sharing.
Developers integrate it into release
pipelines to reduce manual steps during
distribution. The platform focuses on
simplicity and automation. This helps
teams ship macOS software more
efficiently. Explore the repository to
package macOS applications. Thanks for
watching. See you in the next update.