[music]
>> Hi. Welcome to another video.
So, there is a new open source project
called Gemma Chat.
And this one is actually pretty
interesting because it is basically a
local vibe coding app for your Mac
powered by Google's Gemma 4.
And when I say local, I mean actually
local. No API keys, no cloud model, no
monthly subscription. And after the
initial model download, no internet
needed either. You can literally be on a
plane, in a place with no Wi-Fi, or just
working on private code that you do not
want to send to some random server.
And you can still ask it to build stuff
for you. So, let's get right into it.
Now, the funny thing here is that this
project is open source on GitHub under
Ammar Reshi's account. And Ammar is from
the Google AI Studio side.
He leads product design for AI Studio,
and he has been one of the people
pushing vibe coding and agentic
workflows at Google.
But the even more interesting part is
that the official Google Gemma account
is also posting about it, almost like
this is their own thing. They posted
something like offline vibe coding with
Gemma 4, and then described it as an
open source electron app running
entirely on your Mac through Apple's MLX
framework. So, it is not like this is
some random wrapper that nobody at
Google noticed.
It is built around Gemma 4. It comes
from someone inside the Google AI
ecosystem.
And then Google Gemma is basically
showing it off on socials.
Which is honestly pretty cool to see.
Now, just to be clear, Gemma Chat itself
is not presented as a polished official
Google desktop product.
It is an open source proof of concept.
But it really does feel like Google is
saying, "Look, this is the kind of thing
Gemma 4 can do locally." And that is a
much more exciting pitch than just
another benchmark chart. So, what is
Gemma Chat?
Gemma Chat is an electron app that runs
Gemma 4 natively on Apple silicon Macs
using MLX.
If you have used tools like Bolt, Cloud
Artifacts, Lovable, AI Studio Build
Mode, or even Replit style AI builders,
the idea will feel familiar. You type
what you want to build, the model writes
files, and you get a live preview of the
app on the side.
The difference is that this one is
running on your own laptop. You can ask
it to build a landing page, a small
game, a Pomodoro timer, a markdown
previewer, a little dashboard, or a
basic web app. It can write HTML, CSS,
JavaScript, and multi-file projects into
a local workspace. As it writes, the
preview updates in real time, so you can
actually watch the project come
together. That is the main thing that
makes this feel cool.
It is not just a chat box where the
model dumps code and you copy paste it
into VS Code. It has a build mode, a
file workspace, a live preview, and an
agent loop.
So, the model can create files, edit
files, read files, run commands, and
then continue based on the result. And
because everything is local, your
prompts, your code, your conversations,
and your generated files stay on your
machine.
For people who care about privacy,
client work, internal prototypes, or
just not paying API bills, that is a big
deal. Now, there are basically two modes
inside the app. The first one is build
mode. This is the exciting mode. You ask
it to build something and Gemma acts
like a local coding agent. It writes
files into a sandbox workspace, and the
right side of the app shows the preview,
the code, and the file list. So, you can
go from prompt to actual little working
app without touching the terminal.
The second one is chat mode.
This is more like a regular local AI
assistant, but it also has tools. It can
use web search, fetch a URL, do
calculations, and run bash commands.
Obviously, web search and URL fetching
need internet. So, the offline magic
mostly applies to the model and the
local coding workflow. But the fact that
the chat mode also has tools makes it
more useful when you're online.
The app also supports model switching.
You can choose between different Gemma 4
variants depending on your machine and
what you're doing. There is the smaller
E2B model, the recommended E4B model,
and then bigger options like the MoE
model and the 31B dense model. The
smaller models are for speed and lighter
machines, while the bigger ones are for
stronger reasoning if your Mac has
enough memory. According to the repo,
the E4B model is around 3 GB and is the
recommended balance of speed and
capability. The smaller E2B model is
even lighter. And the bigger models need
more RAM. So, if you have an 8 GB Mac,
you probably start with the smaller
ones. If you have 16 GB or 32 GB of
unified memory, then you can start
playing with the heavier options.
And this is where Gemma 4 itself
matters. Google DeepMind released Gemma
4 as their most capable open model
family so far. So, the model itself is
coming from the engineers and
researchers at Google. They are
positioning it for advanced reasoning,
agentic workflows, code generation, long
context, multimodal inputs, and local
deployment. So,
instead of Gemma just being another
small chat model, Google is clearly
trying to make it useful for real
developer workflows.
And Gemma Chat is basically a showcase
of that.
It takes the local model, gives it
tools, gives it a coding workspace,
gives it a live preview, and turns it
into a mini offline coding environment.
So, instead of Google just saying Gemma
4 can do agents, this project shows one
version of what that can look like.
Now, one of the coolest details is how
the app works under the hood. It uses
MLX-LM to run the model weights, but
after that, the model is on your
machine. The app then starts a local MLX
server and streams the model output into
the electron interface. In build mode,
it uses an XML style tool protocol. So,
instead of relying on complex function
calling, the model emits simple tool
actions like write file, edit file, read
file, list files, run bash, and open
preview. That is actually a smart choice
for smaller local models because simple
text formats are often more reliable
than fancy function calling.
The repo even says that small models
handle XML more reliably than JSON
function calling, and honestly, that
makes sense. Another nice detail is live
file streaming. As the model generates a
file, the app can write partial file
content to disk every few hundred
milliseconds.
And the preview reloads while the model
is still typing. So, visually, it feels
like the app is being built live in
front of you.
This is the kind of thing that makes
demos look really good. You ask for a
Chrome Dino style game, or a retro snake
game, or a landing page, and then you
watch files appear and the
preview come alive.
It is very much the vibe coding
experience, but with no cloud model
behind it. There is also voice input,
which is quite cool. It uses local
speech-to-text through Whisper running
in the browser with transformers.js. So,
you can talk to the app and have it turn
that into a prompt. Again, that fits the
whole local first story really well.
Now, let's talk about how I would demo
this. First, I would open the app and
show the model selector. I would
probably choose Gemma 4 E4B because that
is the recommended option.
Then I would go into build mode and ask
it to create something simple like a
retro Chrome Dino game in a single page
with keyboard controls. Then we wait a
bit. Those are the kinds of things
smaller local models can actually handle
pretty well. You are not asking it to
refactor a giant
a giant production code base. You are
asking it to build small web apps,
prototypes, and demos. And to be honest,
that is exactly where a tool like this
makes sense. I do not think this is
replacing Cursor, Claude Codex, or
Gemini 3 Pro for serious production
work. A local 3 GB model is obviously
not going to be as strong as the best
cloud models. But for offline
prototypes, toy apps, quick landing
pages, demos, private experiments, and
student projects, this is a really good
direction. And the cost angle is also
important. There is no subscription
here. The app is open source. The code
is on GitHub. And the model runs
locally. So, you are paying with your
hardware instead of your API bill. If
you already have an Apple silicon Mac,
that is a very attractive deal. You
download the model once, and then you
can keep using it without burning
credits every time you ask it to change
a button color. The app itself is under
the MIT license, and Gemma 4 is released
by Google under Apache 2.0. So, the
licensing story is also pretty friendly
compared to a lot of AI tools. That
matters because local AI is not just
about saving money. It is also about
control, privacy, and being able to
build without asking a hosted service
for permission every time. Now, setup is
also fairly straightforward, at least if
you're comfortable with developer tools.
You need macOS on Apple silicon, Python,
and Node 20 or newer. Then you clone the
repo, install the dependencies with npm
install, and run npm run dev. On first
launch, it handles the MLX
setup and has a command to build a
distributable Mac app, so you can
generate a DMG if you want. That said,
it is still a developer project. It is
not a one-click App Store app yet. So,
if you're a complete beginner, you might
run into setup issues. But for
developers, it should be pretty
manageable. Now, there are some
limitations. First, this is Mac focused
because it relies on Apple's MLX
framework. So, if you're on Windows or
Linux, this specific experience is not
really for you right now.
Second, the first model download needs
internet. So, the offline part starts
after setup. That is not a problem, but
it is worth saying clearly. Third, local
models are still local models. They can
be slower. They can make mistakes. And
the smaller ones are not going to match
the strongest cloud coding models. So,
do not expect it to build a full SaaS
app perfectly in one prompt. Fourth,
some tools inside chat mode, like web
search or fetching a URL, obviously need
internet. So, if you're fully offline,
you should think of this mostly as a
local chat and local coding app, not a
full web connected research assistant.
But even with those limitations, I
really like the idea because the big
promise here is not just another AI
coding app. The promise is that open
models are getting good enough that you
can have a useful coding agent on your
own laptop. No account, no API key, no
server. And that is why the Google angle
is so interesting. First, Google made
Gemma 4. Then their team member from
Google AI Studio world open sourced this
app, and then the Google Gemma account
is posting it as an example of offline
vibe coding with Gemma 4. So, it almost
feels like Google is using a community
style open source repo to show the
future of local AI coding. And if that
is the direction Gemma is going, I am
all for it because we need more of this.
We need more local AI tools that are
actually useful. Not just chat boxes.
Not just model demos. Real workflows. A
coding workspace, file writing, live
preview, model switching, voice input,
and local privacy. That is the stuff
that makes open models matter to normal
developers. Overall, Gemma Chat is not
perfect, and it is clearly still a proof
of concept. But as a demo of what Gemma
4 can do on a Mac, it is pretty awesome.
It shows that local vibe coding is not
just a meme. It is slowly becoming a
real thing. If you have an Apple silicon
Mac, I think this is absolutely worth
trying. Start with the smaller Gemma 4
model, build a few simple apps, test the
iteration flow, and see how far it gets.
Even if it is not your main coding
assistant, it is a really fun look at
where local coding agents are headed.
And honestly, the fact that you can
build a small web app with an open model
on your laptop without Wi-Fi is just
wild. Overall, it's pretty cool.
Anyway, let me know your thoughts in the
comments.
>> [music]
>> If you like this video, consider
donating through the Super Thanks option
or becoming a member by clicking the
join button. Also,
>> [music]
>> give this video a thumbs up and
subscribe to my channel. I'll see you in
the next one. Until then, bye.
>> [music]