[music]
>> Hi. Welcome to another video.
GLM 5.2 is one of the best open models I
have tried for building user interfaces.
And today I want to show you a really
good way to use it.
We are going to connect GLM 5.2 to open
design, which is a free and open source
agentic design workspace.
Then, we will use the combination to
generate a proper landing page, an
analytics dashboard, and even a mobile
interface. I will also take you through
the complete installation and
configuration step-by-step so you can
follow along even if you have never used
open design before. So, let's get right
into it. GLM 5.2 is the latest flagship
model from Z AI. It is a text model with
a 1 million token context window, up to
128,000 output tokens, tool calling,
structured output, and deep thinking.
Those specifications are great, but the
reason I find it interesting here is
that it is very good at long constrained
coding tasks. A good interface is not
just one nice hero section. The model
needs to keep the colors, typography,
spacing, components, and responsive
behavior consistent across the entire
page. GLM 5.2 is quite good at holding
onto those instructions without slowly
turning everything into random gradients
and generic cards. Of course, the model
is only half of this workflow. If you
give Eva a great coding model a vague
prompt like make me a beautiful website,
you can still get the usual AI-looking
result. This is where open design comes
in. Open design is basically an open
source alternative to tools like Cloud
Design. It gives the model a complete
design workflow instead of just an empty
chat box. It includes more than 100
design skills, around 150 design
systems, and a large plugin library. You
can use it for web prototypes, mobile
interfaces, dashboards, decks, images,
and even motion graphics. Most
importantly, the prototypes are made
with real HTML and CSS.
You can preview them, edit them, export
them, and hand them off to a coding
agent. You're not just getting a flat
screenshot that needs to be rebuilt from
scratch later. Open design is also
Apache 2.0 licensed, local first, and
model agnostic. So, you can use Claude,
Codex, Gemini, Qwen, Open Code, or any
OpenAI compatible API.
That last part is how we are going to
bring in GLM 5.2.
Before installing Open Design, we first
need a Z AI API key. Go ahead and get
the API key for the coding plan or
whatever way that you want to use it,
and go ahead and configure it up in Open
Code because that is what we will use to
make it all work. Now, let's install
Open Design. The easiest option is the
desktop app, and this is what I
recommend for most people. Go to
open-design.ai,
click the download button, and choose
the installer for your system. You can
also get exactly the same files from the
releases section of the Open Design
GitHub repository, which I will link in
the description. Once Open Design
starts, it may ask you a few onboarding
questions.
Complete those, and you should land on
the home page.
If you already have coding agents such
as Claude Code, Codex, Cursor, or Open
Code installed, Open Design will detect
them automatically. Just select Open
Code and select the Z AI coding plan GLM
5.2, and you'll be good to go. Now,
let's build something. From the home
page, start a new project. For the
skill, I will choose web prototype, then
choose a design system. Open Design
includes systems inspired by products
such as Linear, Stripe, Vercel, Airbnb,
Apple, Notion, and many others. This is
a big part of why this workflow works so
well. The design system gives GLM 5.2 an
actual visual contract. Instead of
saying "Make it modern," we are giving
it rules for the palette, typography,
spacing, component shapes, motion,
voice, and even things it should avoid.
For the first test, I will use a clean
editorial design system and enter this
prompt.
Create a premium landing page for an AI
research workspace called Northstar.
Use a restrained black, warm white, and
electric orange palette. Include a
navigation bar, a large editorial hero,
an interactive research canvas preview,
a social proof strip, a three-step
workflow, customer results, pricing,
frequently asked questions, and a strong
final call to action. Avoid excessive
cards, gradients, glassmorphism, and
generic AI imagery. Make the page
responsive and use subtle motion only
where it improves hierarchy. Let's send
it and see. GLM 5.2 first works through
the brief, then open design streams the
artifact into the preview. If we wait a
bit, it is now done, and this looks
really good. The hierarchy is clear, the
typography has personality, and it did
not just put every sentence inside a
rounded rectangle. The product preview
also feels connected to the actual idea
instead of looking like a random
dashboard screenshot. The impressive
part
is the consistency. The same orange
accent, border treatment, spacing
rhythm, and type scale continue through
the entire page. This is exactly the
kind of thing models often lose once a
page becomes long.
Now, I do not want to regenerate the
entire page just to make one change. I
can continue the same conversation and
say this.
Keep the current design direction, but
reduce the hero height by 15%. Make the
product preview more information dense.
Add a subtle animated connection between
research nodes, and improve the mobile
navigation.
Do not change the color palette or
typography. Let's send that as well. And
there we go.
It keeps the original visual language
while changing the specific parts I
asked for.
That is the right way to use an AI
design tool.
The first prompt establishes the
direction, and your follow-up prompts
should behave more like focused design
critique.
Now, let's try something very different.
I will create another project, choose
the dashboard skill, and use a darker,
more technical design system.
This time, the prompt is to build an
operations dashboard for a network of
renewable energy sites.
Create a high-density operations
dashboard called GridWatch for
monitoring solar and wind sites. Include
live power generation, regional
capacity, active alerts, a 24-hour
output chart, a map-style site overview,
a maintenance queue, weather risk, and a
compact activity feed. Use a dark
interface with excellent contrast, clear
status colors, and almost no decorative
effects. Prioritize scanability and make
every metric feel operational rather
than promotional. Let's send it and see.
If we wait a bit, here is the result.
This is pretty amazing, to be honest. It
understands that a dashboard needs
density.
We have a proper information hierarchy,
compact controls, readable charts,
status indicators, and a layout that
actually feels useful.
It is not just the landing page with the
headings renamed. This is where GLM 5.2
feels especially strong. It can keep
track of many UI requirements at once.
An open design gives those requirements
structure. The model supplies the
implementation ability, while the skill
and design system supply the taste and
constraints. You can also attach
references or use a more specific design
system when you already know the
direction you want.
A good prompt should describe the
product, the audience, the key sections
or screens, the visual tone, the
interaction priorities, and the styles
you want to avoid.
For example, do not just say, "Make a
SaaS landing page." Say who the product
is for, what the main action should be,
which content needs to appear, whether
the page should feel editorial or
technical, and what should not be used.
Negative constraints such as no
glassmorphism, no giant gradients, and
no excessive cards are surprisingly
useful because they remove the most
common AI defaults. Once you like the
result, Open Design lets you export the
artifact as real HTML. Depending on the
artifact type, it can also export
formats such as PDF, PowerPoint, zip, or
MP4.
You can then hand the HTML and CSS to
CodeX, Claude Code, Cursor, or another
coding agent, and ask it to integrate
the design into your real React,
Next.js, or Vue project. There is one
limitation you should know about. Open
Design's direct BYOK mode is designed
for artifact generation, but it cannot
read, write, or edit the files in an
existing code base. If you want the
agent to modify a real repository,
switch to local CLI mode and use one of
the supported coding agents. You can
still configure that agent to use GLM
5.2 if the agent supports the ZAI
endpoint, but the setup depends on that
particular CLI for generating and
iterating on standalone UI artifacts.
Though, the direct BYOK setup is simple
and works really well.
GLM 5.2 is strong at long detailed UI
implementation and Open Design gives it
the skills, design systems, preview
loop, and export workflow needed to turn
that ability into something consistently
useful. It is not perfect. You should
still check responsiveness, keyboard
navigation, accessibility, contrast, and
whether the generated interactions
actually make sense.
I would also avoid sending one enormous
prompt and expecting the first
generation to be final.
Start with a clear direction,
review the result, and make focused
changes one at a time.
But if you want an open-source UI
generation workflow where you can bring
your own model and keep the output as
real code, this is one of the most
interesting setups you can try right
now.
Overall, it's pretty cool. Anyway, let
me know your thoughts in the comments.
If you like this video, consider
donating through the Super Thanks option
or becoming a member by clicking the
join button. Also, [music] give this
video a thumbs up and subscribe to my
channel. I'll see you in the next one.
Until then, bye.
>> [music and bell]