Hi, in this video I want to give you an
update on the newest features in the
LangChain and LangGraph ecosystem that
came with version 1.1 and version 1.2.
So, for this video I assume you're
already familiar with LangChain on a
deeper level like from watching my crash
course on YouTube or taking my full
courses on Udemy. If not, you can
currently get them as a discount and you
would really support me and my channel
with that. So, thank you very much.
Let's jump straight into the code. As
always, you will get the link in the
description. Okay, I'm now in VS Code
and here on the left you can see the the
LangChain and LangGraph iPython
notebook. So, here is everything
included that you need. So, to um be
able to work with that, you first have
to
create a virtual environment with UV and
and then just run
UV sync. This will automatically install
everything in that environment and now
you can use it in the Jupiter notebook.
Just use the
selected environment and we are good to
go. Okay, so for this video we want to
have a little bit of a dummy use case.
We have a Italian restaurant with a
chatbot where a user can order food and
can get the price of a specific food.
For this we've got a fake database or
just a plain dictionary and two tools
which
um
yeah, allow us to get the prices or
allow us to get an order for specific
item. We also create a customer model
where the customer has got a name, an
address and an order history which is
initially an empty list.
Then we create a a dummy customer, in
this case Mario Rossi, and this lives at
Via Roma 1, Napoli. We also use an
in-memory saver, so this allows us to
get a history, a chat history with a
user.
And yeah, that's it. That's our dummy
setup and
now we can take a look at the new
features. So, the first one is model
profiles. With the new profile attribute
of an LLM instance, we can get a lot of
information about the model that we use
in this case, GPT-4 mini. We can see
what is the maximum of input tokens, the
maximum of output tokens, if tool
calling is enabled, structured outputs,
and also if image inputs are allowed.
So, if we try that out,
then we can see maximum input tokens
128k,
output tokens 16k.
Yeah, tool calling support, structured
output support. So, that can be helpful
explain information, but of course you
can also do a little bit more with it,
which I'm going to show you in the next
part. So, the next is pretty obvious. If
you use multiple models, you can do
something like this. So, you can check
if the model profile has got tool
calling. If that is true, then we want
to use bind tools where we would bind
the tools to the LLM. Otherwise, we
don't want to do that. So, we don't bind
tools to a model that doesn't support
it. Quite simple, but very helpful. The
next is we can also check if a prompt is
larger than the maximum of input tokens.
So, we can do that before we send that
long prompt to the API. You can also
override the profile if you want like
this with in it chat model and here you
pass a dictionary. In this case, maximum
input tokens 100k.
So, this works, but I have to be honest,
I don't really know a use case when you
want to do that other than the OpenAI
registry for the model. Maybe wrong or
something like that. But, in case you
need that, you know how to do it. Okay,
so next I'm going to show you
middleware. So, middleware is a new
feature from LangChain, which is now
usable in combination with the create
agent function, which allows you to
create agents based on LangGraph. So,
this was merged from LangGraph into the
LangChain package. So, what can we do?
We can use create agent, pass a model,
pass tools, and here we pass a third
argument, which is the middleware. So,
in this case, we can use a predefined
middleware from LangChain.
So, the model retry middleware. In this
case, if the API is not available, we
can retry three times, and we can
define an initial delay for the retry,
a backoff factor. In this case, it would
mean uh
first try 1 second, the second one 2
seconds, and the third one 4 seconds.
So, always uh
by two multiplied, and the maximum delay
for the API call 30 seconds. So, on what
errors do we want to retry? On a timeout
error and on a connection error, not on
any generic error. So, to be honest,
this will not work in a demo, of course,
because the API works, and
I will not pull a plug off my internet.
So, um but in case it would not be
available, you would get a multiple
retries. Okay, so the next is pretty
cool, because it combines the new
profile with a middleware. So, in this
case, what we want is to create a
summary if the history of messages gets
very long.
How can we do that? We use the
summarization middleware, which we
import from the middleware package. And
here we can define first a summary
model. So, we could use another model,
so not only GPT-4 mini, the same model
like the chat model, but we could use a
cheaper model, for example, to create
the summary. So, under the hood, that
middleware makes use of the profile. So,
here we can define a trigger argument.
So, if the amount of tokens in the
history exceed 80% of the
maximum input tokens, then this model
will create a summary. But we won't put
everything in the summary, so we will
keep the 20 latest messages, but
everything which is 21, 22 will get
summarized by this model. So, let's try
this out.
And now we can see that if we would use
a long chat history, then we would get a
summary. But we have to do one more
thing because this is of course not the
not even close to the maximum amount of
tokens, but we can update our profile so
that's actually use case for this dummy.
So if we exceed 200 tokens, then we want
a summarization. So now we can do it
again. So we'll give it a new thread ID.
And
now we have to wait a few seconds
because first the history will be
summarized.
So at the end we should get a summary
of this chat history. So here we are. It
worked. So here is a summary of the
conversation. The user's primary goal is
to inquire about the types of pizzas
available. Okay, so this worked. Now
let's have a look at the next
middleware, which is only supported by
OpenAI because OpenAI has got a specific
middleware for that. So in this case we
have to import the OpenAI moderation
middleware class
um from LangChain and we instantiate it
like this. So in this case we define the
model Omni moderation latest. We want to
check for the input. We also want to
check the output that the model has
produced and we also want to check the
results of a tool call because they can
also poison your prompt. We can also
define a violation message where in this
case it's blocked and then we've got a
place holder categories um and we want
the user to keep it um around pizza
orders. We create an agent again and use
the middleware in that function as
argument. Okay. So let's try it out. So
how much is a Diabola?
So this should not trigger the
moderation endpoint.
Here we can see that is the output.
And next
the text is I will find you and hurt
you. So, if you try that, that is of
course a threat. And here we can see
blocked and we can also get the
category, which is in this case
violence. So, this user input will be
blocked by the message that we defined
here. Okay, so that was the middleware.
Now, let's go to another topic, which is
a schema. So, we get with LangChain a
new schema a new structured output,
which is provider strategy. So, we can
only use that if a model supports
structured output. So, in this case
OpenAI does that and we can use provider
strategy, which means we enforce the
structured output via the provider's
native structured output API. In this
case, this is the OpenAI strict JSON
schema. So, we won't do any custom
parsing or tool calling for that. We
will use the native schema of OpenAI for
that. The strict equals true parameter
means that we are enforcing a hard
schema validation. So, if we send the
API the following, so a message with
user as input, the customer, so that is
the name that we gave them him, orders a
margarita and a diavola. So, that are
the orders of that customer. So, we know
the name and the orders and we can also
get the total price by using tool
calling. So, this is
what we expect as result from that call
and we can get the structured response
by accessing the structured response
key. So, at the end we should see the
summary like that. So, structured output
is supported and here we can see
order summary equals custom the customer
is Mario Rossi and the items are
margarita diavola and total for that is
$19.
Just a little warning to be a cautious
if you use that and you type something
like hello, how are you?
Then the following will happen. So,
sometimes it you get a key error,
sometimes
you get a response from that.
Yeah, just try it a few times.
Because, yeah, often enough you get
something like this. So, the API will
try to parse it even though you don't
have anything related to your schema. In
this case, you get guest items
margarita and a total of 8.5. So, this
doesn't make any sense. So, um if you if
you use structure output, you can do
something like this.
Uh in this case, you can
um use a boolean here. So, this will be
used as a classifier, and you can also
give a description. That is also very
helpful for the LLM. So, in this case,
if you do it like this,
Oh, of course it have to save it.
Then you can see the order summary is
the following: order placed equals
false, customize none, items are uh an
empty list, and total is none. So, this
is what you want if you don't have the
correct input. Okay, so let's undo these
changes,
and now let's go
to the next part, which is event
streaming. So, if you want to stream
with LangGraph, you could do something
like this. So, you could a stream
events, and then you could check for the
event type. So, in this case, it would
be on chat model stream, and then you
could extract the chunk like this. So,
from the event, you extract with a key
data, and then you extract with another
key chunk, and then you access the chunk
the content attribute of the chunk to
get the correct message. So, a lot of
unpacking of different stuff. So, this
is the output. So, you stream every
token [clears throat] here. Um but with
version three, this is much easier, as
you can see. This is much more than a
normal for loop. So, you just stream
over every message, and then you access
the text attribute. Nothing
more to do.
There's still a warning because this is
a better
feature, but as you can see much cleaner
syntax, much easier to use. So, if you
want to use streaming and you don't need
to know the specific event, then the
version three is my new recommended way
to perform streaming with the LangGraph.
Okay, so the next feature that we're
going to have a look at is the Delta
Channel. So, what is a Delta Channel?
Sounds quite mysterious, but it's
actually quite easy. So, what do we have
here? This is just a dummy graph that
writes a lot of stuff in a specific
attribute of our initial state. So,
we've got our chat state, which is
this type dictionary and we append a lot
of stuff to this chat log. So, this
Delta Channel is a channel type that
writes only the perspective into the
checkpoint instead of re-serializing the
whole growing list. And the snapshot
frequency of five means that a full
snapshot is not written every time, but
is written every five times. So, reads
only have to replay a handful of deltas,
but you don't have to save everything.
So, a real-world example from LangChain
was a coding agent with over 200 turns
and that agent saved over
5.3 GB of snapshots. With the new Delta
Channel, it was only around 130 MB. But
important without any performance
decrease.
Okay, so let's try and execute that.
So, that is the result. Unfortunately, I
cannot show you the difference in
memory. You somehow have to believe me.
So, this is something that you won't
directly see as output of your graph,
but yeah, when you profile your code,
then you will probably see it yourself.
Okay, so the next topic should be a
little bit more obvious and that is per
node timeout. So, you can Now, when you
you
a node in LangGraph, define a timeout,
then you can also define a retry policy.
So here, if you have a look at add node,
then you can see new is the retry
policy. Oh, there's also cache policy.
And of course here timeout. So this is
very helpful if one of your nodes makes
a call to an let's say API. So you don't
have to define that globally, but you
can directly bake that in your graph. So
I think this is very helpful. So if you
have a look at that, this is a uh a fake
node which sleeps for 5 seconds. We've
got a timeout for 0.3 seconds.
So in this case, we should see an error
if we run it.
So here we can see the node timeout
error. It was raised in the bake node.
Um we can see the run timeout, the time
elapsed before the error was raised, and
it was tried two times because we set
the retry policy to max attempts of
quite easy to use, very helpful.
Okay, so the next functionality are node
level error handlers. So you can
directly define an error handler in your
code. So here we define a graph. So we a
user can place orders, and if an error
happens, the user gets compensated. So
the new function is here,
this function on error handler, and we
will go from the current node to the
compensate node with the command class.
So if an error in a node gets raised and
we register that handler, this will be
executed. So we do it in the place
orders node. Here we register the third
argument error handler, and if an error
gets raised, this error handler will be
executed. So in this case, we going to
define our graph, and the first one uh
the first users will order margarita and
diabola.
So we've got these two pizzas.
And then the other user will make um a
request to get a pizza Hawaii, and this
will fail. So, here you can see the
error was raised, and directly goes to
the compensate node, and here we can see
the result is refund issued. So, when do
you want to use a custom error handler
in comparison to, let's say, a timeout
handler? So, you want to use a custom
error handler if a node can fail in a
way that you can try to recover from in
the graph itself, like rerouting to
another node, instead of letting the
exception kill the whole run. So, that
is the purpose of your custom error
handler. Okay, so the last topic is
quite advanced, which is a graceful
shutdown. You can get that with the new
run control class and the request drain
function. So, when do you want, and why
do you want a graceful shutdown? For
example, um normally you deploy your
agent somewhere in the cloud, for
example, on Kubernetes, and um
the pods that are running often get
restarted, and then, if a pod gets
restarted, the process gets just killed.
So, every intermediate work in a graph
gets lost. With a graceful shutdown, you
can prevent that. So, this is just a
simple dummy graph where we go from one
node to the next. Nothing really happens
here,
but we only sleep for 0.4 seconds here
to
create that graceful shutdown. So, in
this case, we define an instance of run
control, and we use that run control in
the invoke method of our graph. So,
that's that is the way you can use it.
And with this function, we want to
trigger this request drain, so this
graceful shutdown gets simulated. So,
let's try it out.
The graph was stopped gracefully, and
the next node that we want to execute is
baked. So, with auto graceful shutdown,
that would get lost. So, everything that
happens before would get lost, but in
this case, we can just
um continue from the node that we saved,
so from the checkpoint. We pass none as
argument, pass our
old thread object,
and then we just continue with the
graph, and everything gets delivered.
So, this is a very helpful feature if
you use an auto scaler to deliver your
agents in the cloud. And I'm very happy
to see something like that in the
LangChain ecosystem, because this was
definitely missing. Okay, that's it.
Definitely some very cool new features.
Thank you very much for watching, and I
see you in the next video. Bye-bye.