Every week developers release powerful
open-source GitHub projects that help
teams build faster and work smarter. In
this weekly update, we cover top
trending open-source GitHub projects
this week so you can quickly discover
useful developer tools, AI workflows,
and productivity systems. Without
wasting time, let's get started. Welcome
back to Manu AGI tutorials. Here, we
explore the exciting world of AI, latest
AI tools for you, so don't forget to hit
that subscribe button and the
notification bell so you don't miss out
on the latest AI insights. So, let's
start today's video. Project number one,
Hermes agent, framework for autonomous
tool using AI agents. Hermes agent is an
open-source framework from News Research
that enables AI agents to reason, plan,
and execute tasks using external tools.
It combines language models with memory,
APIs, file operations, and multi-step
execution loops to complete complex
workflows. Developers run it locally or
in server environments and extend it
with custom tools and integrations. The
system focuses on practical autonomy and
structured task execution. This helps
teams build capable AI assistants and
automation systems. Explore the
repository to create autonomous agents.
Project number two, Headroom, context
management for AI coding workflows.
Headroom is an open-source tool that
helps developers manage context during
AI-assisted coding sessions. It
organizes project information and
relevant files so language models
receive focused and useful inputs during
development tasks. Developers integrate
it into coding workflows where
maintaining context across large
codebases is important. The system
focuses on improving prompt quality and
reducing noise. This helps teams work
more effectively with coding assistants.
Explore the repository to improve AI
coding context. Project number three,
CopilotKit, framework for embedding AI
copilots into applications. Co-pilot kit
is an open-source framework that helps
developers add AI co-pilots and agent
experiences directly into applications.
It provides UI components, state
management, and agent integration
patterns that connect front-end
interfaces with language models and
back-end workflows. Developers use it
with modern web frameworks to build
interactive AI-powered experiences. The
platform focuses on seamless application
integration. This helps teams ship AI
features more quickly. Explore the
repository to build AI co-pilots.
Project number four, Open Notebook,
open-source notebook for ideas and
knowledge. Open Notebook is an
open-source application designed for
capturing, organizing, and managing
notes in a structured environment. It
provides workflows for storing
knowledge, documenting ideas, and
maintaining personal or team
information. Developers and knowledge
workers use it locally to manage
information without relying on
proprietary platforms. The system
focuses on openness and flexibility.
This helps users build a personal
knowledge base. Explore the repository
to organize your notes. Project number
five, ECC, curated resources for
effective Claude code workflows. ECC is
an open-source repository that collects
guidance, workflows, and resources for
using Claude code more effectively. It
organizes practical techniques,
examples, and operational patterns that
developers can apply during AI-assisted
software development. The project acts
as a learning resource rather than a
run-time tool. This helps teams improve
coding productivity with Claude. Explore
the repository to learn better Claude
code workflows. Project number six,
Cosmos, world foundation models for
physical AI. Cosmos is an open-source
platform from Nvidia that provides world
foundation models designed to understand
and simulate physical environments. It
supports workflows involving video,
spatial reasoning, and physical world
prediction for robotics and AI
applications. Developers use the models
and tools to build systems that reason
about real-world interactions. The
platform focuses on physical AI and
simulation. This helps teams develop
more capable embodied AI systems.
Explore the repository to work with
world models. Project number seven, last
30 days skill. Cloud skill for recent
activity summaries. Last 30 days is an
open-source cloud skill that helps
analyze and summarize information from
the most recent 30 days. It provides
structured workflows that guide
assistance toward recent context when
researching, reviewing, or reporting on
topics. Developers integrate it into
cloud environments as a reusable
capability. The project focuses on
recency-aware information gathering.
This helps users stay focused on current
developments. Explore the repository to
add recent context skills. Project
number eight, PaddleOCR. Optical
character recognition toolkit for
documents. PaddleOCR is an open-source
OCR toolkit that extracts text and
document structure from images, PDFs,
and scanned files. It provides models
and pipelines for text detection,
recognition, and document understanding
across multiple languages. Developers
integrate it into automation, document
processing, and AI workflows. The system
runs locally or in server environments
and focuses on practical OCR tasks. This
helps teams convert visual documents
into usable data. Explore the repository
to process documents with OCR. Project
number nine, plugins. Open framework for
connecting AI to external tools. Plugins
is an open-source repository from OpenAI
that demonstrates how AI systems can
connect with external services through
standardized plugin interfaces. It
defines patterns for exposing APIs,
actions, and capabilities that language
models can use during conversations.
Developers implement plugins to extend
assistance with real-world
functionality. The framework focuses on
interoperability between AI and software
systems. This helps teams build more
capable AI experiences. Explore the
repository to understand plugin
integrations. Project number 10, Mem
Palace, long-term memory platform for AI
agents. Mem Palace is an open-source
memory system that helps AI agents
store, organize, and retrieve
information across sessions. It provides
structured memory workflows that allow
assistants to maintain continuity and
recall relevant context when needed.
Developers integrate it into agents and
productivity systems that require
persistent knowledge. The platform
focuses on memory management and
retrieval. This helps teams build more
context-aware AI applications. Explore
the repository to add persistent memory.
Project number 11, Code Whale, AI coding
assistant for software development. Code
Whale is an open-source AI coding
assistant that helps developers write,
understand, and manage code through
conversational workflows. It combines
language models with project context and
development tools to support common
engineering tasks. Developers run it
locally and integrate it into coding
environments. The system focuses on
improving developer productivity and
code understanding. This helps teams
accelerate software development. Explore
the repository to build coding assistant
workflows. Project number 12, Easy Vibe,
educational toolkit for AI-powered app
building. Easy Vibe is an open-source
project from Data Whale that teaches
developers how to build AI-powered
applications through practical examples
and guided workflows. It covers concepts
such as language models, agents, and
application integration using accessible
learning materials. Developers use it as
a hands-on learning resource. The
project focuses on AI application
development education. This helps
newcomers learn modern AI workflows.
Explore the repository to start building
AI apps. Project number 13, small
lightweight virtual machine for isolated
execution. Small is an open-source
lightweight virtual machine designed for
running workloads in isolated
environments. It provides virtualization
capabilities with a focus on simplicity,
portability, and resource efficiency.
Developers use it to execute
applications securely and experiment
with sandboxed workflows. The system
focuses on compact virtualized
execution. This helps teams create
isolated runtime environments. Explore
the repository to run lightweight
virtual machines. Project number 14,
executor. Simple automation and command
execution utility. Executor is an
open-source tool that automates local
command execution through structured
workflows. It allows developers to
define tasks, chain operations, and
manage execution logic without complex
orchestration systems. The system
integrates into development and
operational environments where
repeatable are important. This helps
teams reduce manual work and improve
consistency. Explore the repository to
automate command workflows. Project
number 15, servesim. Local simulation
server for development testing. Servsim
is an open-source utility that provides
a local simulation environment for
testing application behavior during
development. It creates controlled
conditions where developers can preview
and validate workflows before
deployment. The system integrates into
local development processes and focuses
on rapid iteration. This helps teams
test applications more efficiently.
Explore the repository to run local
simulations. Project number 16, PDF to
interactive lesson. Convert PDFs into
interactive learning content. PDF to
lesson is an open-source application
that transforms PDF documents into
interactive educational experiences. It
extracts content from uploaded files and
converts it into lessons that encourage
active learning and engagement.
Developers and educators run it locally
or in hosted environments to repurpose
existing material. The platform focuses
on educational content transformation.
This helps teams create interactive
learning resources quickly. Explore the
repository to turn PDFs into lessons.
Project number 17, three beans, Nintendo
3DS homebrew utility collection. Three
beans is an open-source project that
provides utilities and tools for
Nintendo 3DS homebrew workflows. It
helps developers and enthusiasts
interact with handheld hardware through
custom software capabilities and
experimentation environments. The
project focuses on practical tooling for
the 3DS ecosystem. This helps users
extend and explore device functionality.
Explore the repository to work with 3DS
homebrew tools. Project number 18, SD
Carapace, REST SDK for temporal workflow
applications. Temporal REST SDK is an
open-source SDK that enables developers
to build durable workflows and
distributed systems using Rust. It
provides APIs for defining workflows,
activities, retries, and long-running
processes that execute through temporal
infrastructure. Developers integrate it
into back-end services that require
reliable orchestration. The system
focuses on fault-tolerant workflow
execution. This helps teams build
resilient distributed applications.
Explore the repository to create
temporal workflows in Rust. Project
number 19, TanStack React Query and
TanStack learning project. TanStack is
an open-source educational project
focused on teaching patterns and
workflows around TanStack technologies.
It provides examples and practical
implementations that help developers
understand state management, data
fetching, and modern front-end
architecture. Developers use it as a
learning resource and experimentation
environment. The project focuses on
hands-on front-end education. This helps
teams improve their React development
skills. Explore the repository to learn
TanStack workflows. Project number 20,
UI server, back-end service for temporal
web interfaces. UI server is an
open-source back-end service that powers
user interface workflows within the
temporal ecosystem. It provides APIs and
operational functionality that support
web-based visibility and interaction
with temporal workflows. Developers
deploy it alongside temporal
infrastructure to manage
workflow-related data and interfaces.
The system focuses on observability and
workflow management. This helps teams
operate temporal environments more
effectively. Explore the repository to
support temporal UI workflows. Thanks
for watching. See you in the next
update.