1,000 AI agents running a marathon. Once
the race starts, almost none of them use
AI at all. Hi, welcome back to Hands-On
AI. I'm Annie and I will join by Casey
Vest. Casey Vest is from Google Cloud
and he led to build this entire gigantic
system. And what you're looking at right
now is 1,000 AI agents running a
marathon. It's open-source code and you
can check the link on the screen. So,
each one of them is real and
independent. They're all running at the
same time. In the last episode, we built
the architecture and today we are going
deeper into the decision that making
running 1,000 AI agents actually
affordable.
>> So, I think Annie, this is the juicy
part. So, like
you know, when do you let an LLM decide
and when do you write code? And I think
it's one of the more important
architectural decisions that we have to
make. So, if we're back here
and we'll go live cuz why not? What
could happen? What bad could happen in a
in a live demo? But, let's go ahead and
plan a marathon route. It's actually
working. So,
it's doing what we were discussing
earlier. It loaded the GIS spatial
engineering skill. It's
going to plan a marathon route.
This takes a little bit of time, but
here we go. So, we have a marathon route
that gets planned.
Cool.
>> Wow.
>> And the regular planner agent just
outputs this text.
>> So, it's loading the skill that it's
using a tool. Load skill to load a skill
so it has knowledge of GIS spatial
engineering and then it's planning the
route.
To actually planning the route. So, oh,
cool.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, here's the route that
it planned, right? Um
And interestingly, you know, we had a
lot of
um constraints on how to plan this
route, but we knew for instance, you
know, it has to be 26.2 mi long and it
also has to be on a city approved street
network. One of the things that we that
we decided to do here is that this 3D
visualization that you see for
Las Vegas is very beautiful.
Um however, we couldn't model every
single street and every single building
in Las Vegas, right? Let me just show
you in GitHub because it does a really
cool rendering of this.
>> Wow.
>> We have a GeoJSON file and if you go
look up GeoJSON, it's a standard. It's a
JSON payload that explains that will
show like coordinates and properties,
features, that sort of thing of a map.
But you can see here in the blue color
that these are all of the roads that are
actually available to us to run this
marathon route on.
Now again, if you were building a real
marathon in Las Vegas, you'd have access
to all the roads. But again, we had a
limitation. So because of that, if I
zoom out again, you can see that we only
had a subset of the roads available to
us in Las Vegas.
So that was one issue that we had.
So because of that,
we couldn't use Google Maps to just give
us a marathon route. Um the other
limitation is that even if we wanted to
use Google Maps, Google Maps has two
um
two route modes for between destinations
that might be interesting. One of them
would be cars or driving directions.
But driving directions honor things like
one-way streets where if you're running
a marathon, you can close the street
down and run in whichever direction you
want, right? Um
and then if we were going to use walking
directions,
there's a unique challenge with Las
Vegas, which is that walking directions
will frequently bring you over bridges,
like walking bridges over major roads,
and through buildings.
>> Yeah.
>> Do Do you remember? So, like it wouldn't
it would be very unlikely that we would
build a marathon route that would make
you run through the Luxor, for example.
The next thing that
people were really interested in is
could we just have Gemini
um build a route for us?
>> I would rely
>> based on
Go ahead.
>> I would have a very smart algorithm to
to like making sure it has an efficient
path. You know, this is similar to my
interview question.
>> [laughter]
>> To like find a route between two
different points. And then I I I I think
I would relying on the deterministic
logic, but I think LLM definitely can
give a good
good route. But if I make a decision, uh
my intuition is more more lean towards
deterministic logic because it's more
reliable and it's give you more
optimal solution.
>> You know what's funny is um
not to give too much away about the
interview process here at Google, but um
at least for our role when I'm
interviewing, I ask a question about how
would you use AI to solve a particular
type of problem? And the real the
the best answers are not to go with full
large language models in in in my
interview question. And it turns out
that's true here as well. So,
um
doing
uh shortest path or a a nearest path um
solution
is actually extremely difficult. We
would call it an NP-hard problem. It's
one of the harder problems in computer
science. But you can see how noisy this
is. And for those of you, and I think
Annie, you've probably done this. If you
try to give this to Gemini,
it might be able to understand it, but
it's going to be very noisy and very
difficult for it to like keep track of
and keep context of as you add more
instructions. But basically, there's an
algorithm out there called a spine and
sprout algorithm. Yeah, so phase one, as
as is this Dijkstra algorithm
um
that takes the road graph. It uses
what's called a a Haversine weighted
edges to stitch landmarks together. Um
then phase two is extending the path
with a serpentine waypoint.
And we use a
uh
Um then we also have to So, we do the
serpentine waypoint,
which will have a series of sequences,
and then we have to trim the last
segment of those sequences so that we
get to exactly
um 26.2188
mi. That's the specific amount of
distance for a marathon officially.
So,
this is deterministic for sure. So,
building the route itself is
deterministic, and very importantly,
it's also unit testable. This is all a
bunch of
gnarly math. Like So, this is why
I felt it would be most most valuable
not to use Gemini and to in fact just
make this part deterministic is that all
of this is computer science algorithms
to solve NPR problems that, you know,
have been built over the last several
decades. Now,
where I did end up using
um
Gemini is in figuring out which
algorithms to use. We used AI Studio cuz
it was just fast enough, but also it was
easy enough for us to do two things. So,
um one of them is code execution here.
Let me make sure my screen is big
enough.
So, we used AI Studio in this case
because I also had um
non-developers who were also trying to
figure out like what would the best
algorithms be.
So, what we did is we we uploaded, you
know, from our files the network uh dot
JSON file. So, that was the GeoJSON file
that I showed you earlier with all of
those coordinates in it.
And then we described in our prompt all
of our constraints.
And then most importantly, we enabled
code execution here.
And that allowed it us and we could also
do grounding with Google search. So,
these two things allowed us to have
Gemini in AI studio. Let me just click
that button. Gemini in AI studio was
able to
look up algorithms for solving problems
like this using its search tools and its
and its own knowledge. And then write
Python code using code execution that we
could use as starting point. I then took
that and I brought it to tools like
Gemini CLI and I said, "Here's a
starting point. Might not be perfect.
Here are our constraints. I want this to
be unit testable. I want you to do like
deep code review on this." And we
iterated on these algorithms a number of
times to get to where we are today.
>> That is so smart. I will try this way to
do research next time.
>> So, the routing logic is fully
deterministic. But, this is the
interesting part. You know, Casey still
used AI to help choose the deterministic
algorithm. Just not at run time.
And that is a pattern behind this whole
system. You know, we use the model where
it actually helps and we skip the model
where it doesn't. They applied that same
idea again inside the simulator and that
is where the real trick lives.
>> So, that's how we determined it in the
planner agent. Right? And then there's
two other locations where we had to make
similar decisions. The simulator is an
agent, but what if the work is really
mechanical? So,
but it lives inside of an agent
framework. So, you still want an agent
life cycle, right? And you still want
things like A2A to communicate with it.
You still want telemetry. Um but you
don't want an LLM call for something
that might be a deterministic or a
procedural set of steps. And you know,
you've written a bunch of agents before,
Annie, so you know, like sometimes you
write a bunch of tools that have your
deterministic logic in it.
And all you really need an agent to do
is is call tool number one and then call
tool number two and then call tool
number three, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, so the question is like do you
want an LLM to do that or
do you or do you need an LLM to do that?
>> Uh depends on the use case. If uh if you
know, sometimes for the case that you
cannot you do not want to add
deterministic logic, it's good for LLM
to like decide because sometimes you
cannot handle all the use all the cases
with use different user input. Then uh I
think LLM decide is a good approach,
especially cover different edge case.
And then if it's a specific use case,
for example, I just want a planning,
like for example, specific route, I
might just want to add deterministic
logic to bypass the LLM uh generation
and I just add some deterministic logic
to like force it to do certain thing. Uh
actually I have to use this check for
some of my agents this time that I have
to like um use callback with before tool
call to bypass something and then uh to
do some other deterministic logic in the
back end. Yeah. Um yeah, it's like
really depend on use case for my
situation. I'm curious for this use
case, how do you handle that?
>> Yeah, so in this use case, the simulator
agent's really fascinating because there
are a couple of things where we might
want the LLM to to be a part of decision
making, right? Some heuristics, um that
sort of thing. But to run a simulation
is a relatively straightforward
approach. You need to set the simulation
up. You need to run the simulation
itself.
Um and to run the simulation, what we
chose is essentially we call it like
server side ticks, which is a a term
built from like game development. So
like in in games,
when you have a server, a centralized
server, it usually has a tick where
every
couple of milliseconds or every second,
it will essentially try and figure out
the state of the entire system and it
keeps track of that state. So, that's
what we did here as well. So, you can
think of the simulator as like the game
server and you can think of the runners
as little game players that are all
running around inside of the game. And
so, the simulator's trying to figure out
where are all of my runners? What is
their current state? What are their
properties?
So, that's what we did here. Um
So, here you can see the architecture of
the simulator agent. Um this is inside
of, you know, the agent.py for the
simulator.
So, we still want to use the agent
paradigm or the agent's model to
organize the complex workflow, but we uh
want to cheat time as much as possible
and be as efficient as possible on the
execution.
So, if we go down to pre-agent, see,
pre-race agent here.
Um
this is the trick. So, pre-race agent
and the tick agent are both LLM agents
and they have a model, but [snorts] if
we look at line 252,
you can see in this comment here, the
model is required by the LLM agent as in
order to create the object, but it's
never actually called because the the
before model callback, this is an ADK
feature of callbacks, the before model
callback intercepts every invocation and
returns deterministic tool calls. So, in
this case, the pre-race thing just needs
to set up and call a couple of tools in
order to set up the environment.
>> Wow.
>> it needed to do the same thing every
time, but I still wanted to have it
function exactly like any other ADK
agent, so I could get the life cycle
management, I could hook into the
callbacks, I could get the telemetry,
all that stuff.
>> Wow. So, before you're even using the
model, you have this callback intercept
this lifecycle and then just uh switch
to your determines the logic to bypass
the actual LLM use.
Uh
>> That's right.
>> That's so cool.
>> And there you know, this is important.
Um
it saves money, it reduces latency, and
it guarantees reliability in a part of
the agent system where we actually need
it.
>> I did a similar thing with one of my uh
live turn that live agent that you know,
when in the voice context, if you have a
live agent I have voicing voice out uh
with two call at like latency so that
the voice is not as fast uh as not using
two call. So I basically also using
before two call back to bypass the two
call so that it will
>> Right.
>> return to me immediately.
>> I'm also still adhering to the uh ADK
paradigm. Function call will still set
up a tool call using ADK's own client
libraries and and publicly, you know,
provided interfaces to do the exact same
thing. And we can even set session
state, you know, context state, that
sort of thing here.
Um and that's exactly how this works.
Yeah. So
And it's the same thing in
uh
in the ticks. So I mentioned the ticks
as well.
Um if I scroll down a little bit here,
like we can see the tick callback does
the same thing. The tick callback only
ever needs to call advance tick and
check if the race is complete. And
because I know that that's all it has to
do, I want to cut down on any latency. I
don't need the LLM calls. And
um
just because of the runners especially
and and because of all of the things
that are happening when we run the
simulation, there's already a huge
amount of context and like messages
being passed to Gemini. So any places
where we can optimize it, this cut down
on the the time and space. So, um this
is a really efficient model where you do
have some areas in a code base where you
know they need to be deterministic,
you can get away with that even within a
framework like ADK and still adhere to
ADK and get all of the features that are
available to you. It would be
easy to write this where you short
circuit like tool calling and your
callback does all the work by itself,
but then you lose things like visibility
and telemetry. So, I would recommend to
anyone out there, if you feel like you
need to do a similar thing, you know,
use a model like this and tear apart
this code base and and steal it for
yourself.
>> That is so cool. So, I feel like it's a
agent
surface, but but beneath below the
surface it's the deterministic normal
like you know, deterministic logic,
deterministic deterministic call. Do you
think it's still an agent?
>> Um yes. So, the the the simulator agent
is our most sophisticated like it's in
ADK we would call it a multi-agent
system even though this whole thing is
like many independent agents that are
like network disconnected from one
another. The simulator agent actually
has um
in ADK we call them
um
workflow agents. So, the it uses a
looping agent, it uses a sequential
agent, um things like that. So, it is a
multi-agent architecture with
sub-agents. Um so, I still think it's an
agent even if some pieces are are
deterministic.
>> Yeah, this is this is really cool cuz
I've been struggling a lot with um how
do you build a hybrid system where you
still keep the advantages of agent
system but also
um adding more control and basically
uh have a good balance of you know, use
the deterministic logic when it need to
but rely on AI for
uh when it's AI is doing it better. When
it's a time for AI to do in a better
job. So, how do you build a hybrid
system? I think this is a really cool
way for us to, you know, first
we have all the benefit of educating
agents. We have We have like We have
benefit of life cycle, this tool call,
this telemetry, observability, and more.
But, at the same time, we can like
adding this one small chip by bypass the
model call back. It's really cool demo
demonstration of how you can build
hybrid system, how how you can really
have a good balance of those. It's
really cool.
>> Yeah. Yeah, thank you. Um we did the
same thing with runners just briefly.
So, the runner agent uses an LLM,
but the runners are We have a lot of
them. That's our most scalable agent in
terms of how many we're trying to run or
simulate at the same time.
>> Yeah.
>> And any latency is going to be a
problem. So, we also built what we call
the autopilot runner, which you can see
on screen here. And it just extends or
um augments the behavior of the regular
runner agent. So, that's what get base
agent does here. But then, instead of
calling the LLM,
it makes its own decisions using some
heuristics and a bunch of uh data that
we pulled from Gemini deep research
about how runners behave. So, it's all
code-based, but that allows the
autopilot agents to run within
milliseconds um whenever they get
called.
And that's how we could get The back end
can support up to 10,000 simultaneous
agents. The front end is this very
beautiful three-dimensional
visualization, and it's constrained by
Chrome and memory management, CPU, and
GPU. So, we were only able to show 1,000
on the screen uh during the demo, but um
that's how we got to that scale.
>> Cool. So, you talk about you're showing
1,000 uh like session agent session at
the same time. And I know that now we
cover you We understand architecture. we
are deep dive into the agent code, we
are understanding how it loading the
skill and we are understanding how to
balance the LM and the deterministic
logic, but still what is the real magic
behind everything to so that all the
sessions can run at the same time. What
is the trick?
>> Yeah, that's a great question. So I
think to do that I want to just dive in
a little bit to things like the agent
life cycle so we can see how things
work. So
what we're looking at right here is one
of the developer tool UI's that we built
into race condition. It's the agent
telemetry dashboard and we can see
actually some messages that are coming
in right now.
And
what you're watching is every row is a
real ADK life cycle event from a real
agent session.
And we have rows that say like starting
and finished or model start, model end,
that kind of thing.
And we also have them grouped by session
IDs and the sequence of the message
within that session.
So
this is pretty cool. I think a thing to
know is that all of these are also
messages that are passed over the
gateway using pub sub as a broadcasting
mechanism and then get emitted over a
web socket to this front end UI. So if I
click run simulation now this is live.
We should hopefully
see messages. Yeah, so the user said run
a simulation, right? That was me.
So that's that's what we're doing there.
And now we can see that the planner with
eval is doing a lot of the heavy lifting
right now.
It'll be interesting to see how fast
this is considering you know, Gemini
latency and API calls and all of that.
But now we can see actually a number of
agents that are running including these
runner autopilots. So, they all got
messages. Let me see if I can scroll to
like tool end from process tick. So,
the simulator agent has a sub agent that
is a tick processor, right? So, it sends
a process tick message event to the
runner autopilot agent and and we've
already scrolled past it here. We can
see
this is how many events are running in
the system live.
Um and we can see things like latency
and total events here. Um total number
of tokens. So, Gemini 3 flash preview
has 350,000 tokens. So, as you can see,
this is a decent amount of of work,
right?
>> So, you are looking at about 350,000
tokens, and that is not zero.
But, here is the key. Those tokens are
not from the route math. The route math
is deterministic code. So, that part is
basically free. The token come from the
AI doing judgment. You know, which
landmarks should we include? Does the
timing make sense? Is the plan safe and
runnable? The model reasons through that
once and then before the race and then
1,000 uh runners just take over. And
they actually never call the model
itself. So, adding more runners does not
add more tokens. The AI decides and the
code runs.
>> So, this is the firehose of everything
that's happening in the system.
Um and with a thousand runner agents, it
means that we've got these a thousand
independent ADK sessions,
each one with its own state, right? And
we're running we happen to be running
this on Cloud Run, but um these
processes are stateless and we have to
run the real system in production, we
had over 50
uh
instances of the service for runner
autopilot on Cloud Run. So, that's 50,
you know, unique server processes that
are running on Cloud Run.
All stateless. So, session state has to
live somewhere, and it has to be shared
because these runners are keeping track
of the sessions throughout the history.
You can see that this is the 67th turn
on this session for this runner. This is
one unique runner. And really, that was
one of the first things that broke for
us. So, when you're building at scale at
scale
for stateless sessions where you have to
do large scale, one of the first
question is where does the state live? I
think we have to talk a little bit about
ADK and session stores. So, ADK, by
default, comes with a handful of session
stores automatically available. Um,
Annie, do you know which what which
session store, when you're running ADK
locally and you're just developing your
own agent, which session store it uses
by default?
>> Yeah, so ADK, uh, has in-memory session
service. Basically, it uses in the run.
And it also has the option like database
session service. It can use your own
database solution. For example, OL DB
or, uh, SQLite, Cloud SQL, stuff like
that. And then there's also option, uh,
called Redis session service. You can
like using our agent runtime. I'm going
to pass it back to you, Casey. So, how
the system using,
uh, memory? How does, uh,
how does the session service configured
here?
>> Yeah, exactly. So, first of all, very
thorough response. I love that. Um,
and you're right. So, we had a couple of
challenges with the default options that
were available to us in ADK. Um,
in-memory doesn't work when you have
multiple session or multiple instances
of your agent running at the same time,
like 50 instances on Cloud Run,
because then your session state is only
localized to a single instance. And I
needed to share the session state across
all those instances because we never
know which one the global load balancer
will give the next message to.
But I also couldn't use the What do we
call it now? The agent platform sessions
in in Gemini enterprise agent platform
because this agent was running on Cloud
Run instead of running in agent runtime.
Uh and it was running on Cloud Run so I
could get the scalable characteristics I
needed.
>> Yeah, but it could
Right?
>> What's that?
>> But it takes the it takes time to load
in this, right? Uh I think the right so
only faster.
>> Yeah, so the third option, of course,
would be like a database like AlloyDB,
and I did try that. But But
the overhead of the SQL calls, the
queries to retrieve and store session
state, and the transactions that were
required were actually too slow, and
they became one of the bottlenecks. So,
I had to come up with a creative
workaround. So, one of the techniques I
was using in this architecture already
to try and keep things fast and with
really low latency was using Google
Cloud's Memory Store, which is managed
Redis. And so, my question was, could I
use Redis as a session store? Well, ADK
doesn't have that by default, but what I
found that I really was very happy about
is that there is a repo that Google
maintains with community contributions
called Google ADK Community. You can
find it on GitHub. And in Google ADK
Community is a Redis session service
that a community member had written. So,
I used it, and then my agents were as
fast as I needed them to be. So, that
was one of the key things that I was
able to do.
>> Kudos to that community contributor.
>> Yeah, exactly, exactly. Um I was really,
really, really pleased with that. And
then,
um just to give them like a shout-out
here, you know, all you have to do um in
your Python code is pull in the Google
ADK Community repo and then you can uh
configure your session service. In this
case um
the Redis session service in my repo is
a sub class that does a few extra tweaks
just for a little bit of additional
performance, which is that it prunes
events and prevents blob growth. So just
making sure that we keep everything as
streamlined as possible because again, I
have a thousand simultaneous sessions.
We send them all a message over pub/sub
instantly and get all the responses back
and we have to collect them as fast as
as possible.
Um there's way more to go into with this
and you know there's maybe not enough
time, but that's where um I will
encourage everybody to explore this code
base and let me actually just share with
the community uh the everybody who's
listening. One of the ways you can share
that you can explore this code base,
whether you're using things like Cloud
Code, Cursor, or like Gemini ICIL, is
that it includes
skills for your AI harnesses or AI dev
tools, including an exploring the code
base skill, which will explain to your
um AI coding assistant like Gemini CLI
how to look into this code base, where
things are and then you can ask a
question like, you know, how did we get
a highly efficient Redis session service
for extremely low latency scalable
sessions with agents?
>> Well, no wonder why I started this repo.
My AI is really efficient with all the
AI.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, thanks for, you know, creating a
skill. That's pretty pretty helpful.
>> Thank you for this great session, Casey.
You you're I learned so much from this
conversation.
>> And just
>> Yeah, I had so much fun exploring it
with you again.
>> Stay tuned and we have more episode
coming up. And again, thank you so much
for watching this and I'll see you next
time. Um, bye.
>> Bye.
>> [music]
[music]