Open AI's codeex app powered by the GPT
5.5 genuinely feels like a true AI super
app that can practically do everything.
Yesterday I made a video showcasing the
full capabilities of codecs from data
analysis to full application development
as well as building out fullon games to
web development, browser use, and even
computer control workflows. And when it
comes to browser use and computer use,
GBT 5.5 is honestly incredible because
on the OS world verified, a benchmark
that measures whether a model can
autonomously operate real computer
environments, the GPT 5.5 reaches a 78.7
percentage, also being significantly
more token efficient. This is a massive
step forward for realworld autonomous AI
agents. And now when you combine GPT 5.5
with Codeex, things get even crazier cuz
Open AI recently launched browser use
within Codeex as a plug-in. And this is
to help fully close the build and verify
loop for local deployment. You can now
ask Codex to build your front end, for
example, and then actually test it out
with the GPT 5.5 model like a real user
by clicking through the application
itself. And you can essentially have
codecs visually see everything the user
sees through vision capabilities while
simultaneously inspecting console and
network logs to debug and automatically
fix issues that it encounters. This is
truly a major step forward cuz it brings
in fully autonomous coding agents
capable of delivering highquality fully
tested software changes with minimal
human intervention. Not just that, this
is something that will help you set up
automations, help you control your
computer to automate basic
computer-based tasks as well. For
example, with browser use enabled, GPT
5.5 and codeex is able to handle far
more within a workflow across the
browser, files, documents that you have
within your computer. In this case, it's
able to open up a whole home setup that
is basically testing out all the visual
inputs, interacting with the web app,
testing out the user flow, clicking
through pages, capturing screenshots,
and continuously iterating on what it
sees until the task is successfully
completed. If you want the best AI
tools, workflows, and drops before
everyone else, join my free newsletter
with the link in the description below,
which is completely free. And what's
funny is that they know that a lot of
people are using this browser use and
computer use feature within Codeex,
which is why they implemented a huge new
change, which makes it much faster. In
fact, computer use now runs this use
case 42% faster in today's Codeex apt
update, which is incredible. And
genuinely, this is the first time we
have seen large Tangish models operate a
GUI as fast as an actual person. And
honestly, it feels surreal in these
different use cases with Codeex enabling
computer and browser use. And the best
part about Codeex is that it is
something that is completely free and
you can install it for Windows and Mac
OS devices. Now, I've already made a
full-on video showcasing this. So, I
highly recommend that you watch this cuz
I showcase almost all of the features of
Codeex and what you can do with it. So,
this is something that will get you
easily started. But now once you have it
installed, we can get started on what
you can actually do with Codex. After
installing and logging in with Codex,
what you will notice is on the main
dashboard, you have a couple of
different options. Now, I would
recommend that you keep this on the
default permissions. And what you want
to do first is start up a new project
from scratch. This is to help contain
everything. But when you are to use the
/act command or if you are to press this
plus sign and then click on plugins, you
will see that browser use has been
already installed within your codeex
app. If it isn't, you can head over to
plugins. You can search up browser use
and then you can install this. But what
you can now do is use this directly
within the chat panel. This is
essentially your main dashboard. And you
can command browser use to be enabled by
simply using the app command. And then
you can select it and then request it to
do almost anything. Whether that is
sending emails, testing out a checkout
flow on local host or just simply
opening up a page. This is essentially
browser use task where you can control
your browser with codecs. And in my
opinion, you don't need much
intelligence with this unless if it is a
meticulous task that you're giving it.
So, if you want, you can set the
intelligence to low. And this way,
you're not able to run through your rate
limit as fast as it used to be if you
set it to a higher intelligence. But you
can see over here, I simply enabled
browser use to open up World of AI on
YouTube, and it was able to open up this
web page. Now, what's nice is you can
even set up automations with browser
use. So you can even have a setup
directly within codeex to essentially
send out emails or simply scrape leads
using browser use and then have that
automation set by creating that and then
having it enabled to use that plugin
every single time at a certain time like
at 9:00 a.m. Just as an example, I can
say use browser use every single day to
scrape new AI topics and create a PDF of
new AI news. And I can simply go ahead
and click on create and there we go. So,
it's simple as that. Our automation is
completed. And after running that
specific automation, this is where it
created a fullon PDF. It scraped all the
sources and actually listed out all of
them at the bottom of the page, which
you can see over here. But the fact that
it's able to do this quite rapidly and
use the GPT 5.5 efficiently is the best
part about this because not only is it
able to control your browser, but it's
able to do deep analysis and help you
execute tasks like this on a regular
basis. Here is a super simple notes app
that I had requested the GPT 5.5 to
actually generate. Now what I can
showcase is I can have browser use
enabled and I can have it test out this
user flow of my applications. So I can
say test out the nodes app and
essentially this is going to have it
work upon testing out the exact user
flow and this is where it can interact
with all the components of my notes app.
So on the left hand side you can see
that it is executing upon all these
different tasks. It added a new task and
it's able to write up new notes and then
add it as well. And it's pretty
important when you use browse use with
these different user testing flows
because it can test out different signup
login flows. You can click through
entire applications like a real user to
make sure everything is functioning
properly as well as catching bugs,
console and network errors. And you can
even essentially have it automated.
Next, I had just wanted to create a
chess game to showcase that browser use
is something that can actually test out
a full-on development of your
application. In this case, I can have it
actually play chess. So, I can say, can
you play chess for me? And this is a way
for you to test out if all the functions
of your application is perfect or not.
And you can intelligently prompt browser
use to be invoking certain functions
like if it is catching a bug within the
console or if it notices something with
browser use visually, it is able to
execute upon that task and it's able to
solve and resolve that particular
console log or that issue that it
visually saw to make sure that it's able
to catch and fix issues on standby. But
just take a look at this. This is where
we have browser use enabled and it's
able to automate the ability to play
chess for example. Not just that guys,
it's able to execute task off of your
computer which is why I had mentioned
computer use. This is where you can have
it execute a task like organizing a
bunch of different random files off of
my desktop. This is where I have bunch
of different thumbnails that I have
previously used for my channel and all
of them are quite unorganized. The
titles don't look properly formatted.
So, this is where I'm going to tell
browser use to actually go onto my
computer, computer use technically, but
have it go onto my computer, go over to
my desktop, and organize all of them.
And you can see that it did it quite
rapidly and it was able to numerically
format all of them in a proper format
all the way from 1 to 15. Now another
super use Now another super cool use
case of computer use is combining codecs
with Apple's iPhone mirroring app which
basically lets GPT interact with apps on
your phone through Mac. Now, this is a
little less precise compared to native
desktop apps since it's relying on
visual clicks and screen interpretation,
but it genuinely works surprisingly
well. Some insanely useful app workflows
that it could be used for is testing
mobile app UX flows, automating social
media posting workflows. You can manage
message as well as work on sending out
different emails, mobile game testing,
QA testing for iOS, and so much more.
We're honestly entering an era where AI
agents can operate across browsers,
desktops, and even phones like real
users. If you like this video and would
love to support the channel, you can
consider donating to my channel through
the super thanks option below. Or you
can consider joining our private Discord
where you can access multiple
subscriptions to different AI tools for
free on a monthly basis, plus daily AI
news and exclusive content, plus a lot
more. Now, there's so much more to this
and I highly recommend that you test it
out, which is why I've really emphasized
in my video yesterday to switch to
Codeex because honestly with the usage
limits that Open AI provides with their
paid tiers, it's a lot better than
Claude Code at the moment, which is why
I had made this video talking about
Codeex and this is an app that will
practically let you do almost anything
in one single area. So, I highly
recommend that you take a look at
Codeex. I'm not promoted or sponsored by
them. I'm just recommending something
that might be useful for many of us
users. But with that thought, guys, I
hope you enjoyed today's video and got
some sort of value. I'll leave all these
links in the description below. But with
that thought, guys, thank you guys so
much for watching. Make sure you join
the second channel by subscribing. Take
a look at our newsletter, join the
Discord, follow me on Twitter. Lastly,
make sure you guys subscribe, turn on
notification bell, like this video, and
please take a look at our previous
videos so that you can stay up to date
with the latest AI news. But with that
thought, guys, have an amazing day.
Spread positivity and I'll see you guys
fairly shortly. Peace out, fellas.