[music]
Hi, welcome to another video. So, Google
AI Studio has been getting a lot of
really interesting vibe coding updates
recently, and the newest ones are
actually pretty important because AI
Studio is no longer just a place where
you chat with Gemini or generate a small
web app. It can now build Android apps
directly inside your browser. And Google
has also added a new design variations
option that helps you instantly generate
and apply different UI layouts without
writing some long design prompt. And
honestly, this is kind of great. Now, I
have talked about AI Studio Build
before, and I still think it is one of
the most underrated app builders out
there, especially because it is
connected to the Gemini ecosystem, and
the free tier is usually very generous.
But Android app generation changes the
story quite a bit because previously if
you wanted to build an Android app, even
a simple one, you usually had to install
Android Studio, set up the Android SDK,
configure the emulator, deal with
Gradel, create the project structure,
understand Cotlin or Java, and then
start building the actual app. And if
your machine is not very powerful,
Android Studio can be quite heavy. The
emulator alone can make your laptop
sound like it is preparing for takeoff.
But now with AI Studio, the workflow is
much simpler. You can go to AI Studio,
open the apps or build section, choose
the Android app option, describe what
you want to build, and Gemini will
generate the Android project for you. It
can create a Cotlin and Jetack compose
app, set up the Gradal files, generate
the manifest, create the resources,
build the UI, and then show you the app
running inside a cloud Android emulator.
So you're not just getting a random code
snippet. You are getting an actual
Android project that you can preview,
interact with, iterate on, and
eventually download. That is the big
deal here. For beginners, this lowers
the barrier to Android development
massively. You can build a small habit
tracker, a notes app, a workout timer, a
study app, a simple finance tracker, a
mood journal, a tiny AI companion app,
or basically any simple mobile utility
without spending 2 hours setting up
tools before you even see a button on
screen. And for developers, I think this
can be really useful as a prototyping
tool. If you have an idea for a mobile
app, you can describe it, get a working
Android prototype in the browser, test
the flow, ask for changes, and only then
decide if the idea is worth turning into
a proper project. That is a much better
workflow than starting with an empty
Android Studio project and spending half
the day fighting boilerplate. Now, from
what Google describes, the Android
builder is focused on modern Android
development. Though it uses cotlin,
jetpack compose, material 3 and the
standard Android project setup. That is
good because compose is the direction
Android UI has been going in for a while
now. It is much more AI friendly than
old XML layouts because the UI is
code-based, declarative, and easier for
a model to generate and edit. You can
also preview the app in a cloud
emulator, rotate it, test the interface,
and keep prompting Gemini to fix issues
or add features. So let's say you ask it
to make a meditation timer app. It can
generate the initial UI. Then you can
say add custom session lengths, add a
history page, make the timer persist if
I leave the app, or make the design more
minimal and calm. And instead of
manually editing several files yourself,
you can keep iterating through prompts.
That is the type of thing that makes
this exciting. Now there is also an
installation workflow for real devices.
You can connect your Android phone and
install the app through the browser
using web USB.
This is important because Android
emulators are useful but they are not
enough. Mobile apps need to be tested on
real devices. The screen size,
permissions, performance, battery
behavior, keyboard behavior, scrolling
feel, and even small touch interactions
can feel different on a real phone. So,
the fact that you can build in the
browser, preview in the emulator, and
then install it on a real Android phone
is pretty amazing for quick testing.
There is also support for Play Console
internal testing, which means if you
have a Google Play developer account,
you can package the app and push it to
an internal testing track. Now, this
does not mean AI Studio magically makes
your app production ready or approved
for the Play Store. You still need to
test properly, check permissions, check
crashes, check privacy behavior, check
Play Store policies, and make sure the
app is not doing anything weird. But as
a path from idea to testable Android
app, this is really nice. Now there are
some limitations as well. Android apps
in AI studio are currently more limited
than web apps. The full stack features
like Firebase integration, secrets
management, workspace APIs and
multiplayer support are mainly for web
apps, not Android apps. The Android app
generation is also focused on cotlin and
jetack compose. So you should not expect
Java projects, old XML layout workflows,
NDK support, where OS, Android TV or
complex multiodule projects from this
yet. And for Android projects, the docs
focus on downloading the project as a
zip. So don't assume it has the exact
same workflow as the web app builder. So
I would not call this a full replacement
for Android Studio, at least not yet. I
would call it a prompt to prototype
Android builder. And that is still very
useful because a lot of people don't
need a perfect production app on the
first try. They need a working first
version. They need something they can
tap on. They need to see if the idea
makes sense on a phone. And this is
where AI Studio can be really powerful.
Now, the second update is design
variations. And I actually think this
might be one of the most important vibe
coding features for non-designers.
Google basically said that describing an
aesthetic in a prompt can be tough. So,
they made a button for it. And that is
exactly the problem when you are
building with AI. Writing feature
prompts is usually easy. You can say
make a to app, add a calendar, add
login, add a chart, or save the data.
But design prompts are much harder
because how do you describe taste? You
might say make it modern, but modern can
mean anything. You might say, make it
premium, and the model might just add
dark gradients and glass cards
everywhere. You might say, make it
minimal, and it might remove everything
useful from the interface. This is why
so many AI generated apps have the same
look. They have big cards, random
gradients, huge border radius, too much
spacing, generic icons, and a layout
that looks okay in a screenshot, but
feels very template-like when you
actually use it. Design Variations tries
to solve this by making the design
process more visual. Instead of typing a
long aesthetic prompt and hoping Gemini
understands your taste, you can generate
multiple UI variations, explore them,
and apply the one you like. So if you
are building a dashboard, a mobile
utility, a landing page or an app
interface, you can quickly try different
layout directions without rebuilding
everything manually. That is really
useful because in most app builders, the
first version of the app is rarely the
final design. The functionality might be
fine, but the layout feels off. The
spacing is weird. The colors are too
loud. The typography does not match the
use case. The app feels too playful when
it should feel professional, or too
boring when it should feel fun.
Previously, you would need to keep
prompting the model again and again.
Make it more polished. Make it less
corporate. Make the layout denser. Make
the card smaller. Make it feel like a
real product. And sometimes that works.
But sometimes the model changes too much
or makes the wrong part worse. With
design variations, the loop becomes much
easier. You can generate a few visual
options, compare them, and choose the
one that feels closest. That turns
design prompting into design selection.
And for a lot of people, that is exactly
what they need. Most people can tell
which design looks better when they see
it. They just cannot always describe it
perfectly in words. So, this is one of
those features that sounds simple, but
can make the whole app building
experience feel much better. Now, I do
hope Google keeps improving this and
makes it more controllable over time.
For example, it would be really useful
if you could generate variations only
for a specific screen or only for a
component or preserve the exact layout
but change the visual style or preserve
the style but change the information
density because design is not just
colors. It is spacing, hierarchy,
layout, contrast, motion, state
handling, empty states, loading states
and all of that. But even as a single
click feature, this is a really good
direction. And when you combine it with
Android app generation, it becomes even
more interesting because mobile app
design is tricky. You have less space.
Touch targets need to be comfortable.
Text needs to be readable and the
interface needs to feel native. So, if
AI Studio can generate Android apps and
also help you explore better UI
directions quickly, that makes it much
more practical for people who want to
build real mobile prototypes. Now, I
still want to be very clear. Do not
blindly publish whatever AI Studio
generates, especially for Android apps.
If your app uses permissions like
camera, microphone, location,
notification access, usage access,
overlay permissions, background
services, contacts, files, or anything
sensitive. You need to inspect
everything carefully. AI can generate
working code, but working code is not
always safe code, efficient code, or
policy compliant code. You should still
check the manifest, review permissions,
test on multiple devices, check battery
usage, check error handling, and make
sure your app does not collect or expose
anything it should not. Also, pricing
and accounts still matter. AI Studio
itself is very generous. But if your app
uses Gemini APIs, Google Cloud, Play
Console, Firebase, or other paid
services, you need to understand the
cost side. And if you want to publish on
Google Play, the developer account has a
onetime $25 fee. So this is not magic.
It is still software development. But
the starting point is getting much
better and that is the part I really
like. AI Studio is slowly becoming a
full creative coding environment. You
can start with a rough idea, generate an
app, preview it, edit it, try different
designs, install it on a real device,
and then keep iterating. For students,
hobby builders, indie hackers, and
people who just want to prototype an
idea quickly, this is amazing for sure.
For professional developers, I think it
is more of a fast exploration tool. You
use it to generate the first version,
test the concept, maybe download the
project, and then continue properly in
Android Studio or your normal workflow.
Overall, this is a really good update.
Android app generation makes AI Studio
much more serious as an app builder and
design variations fixes one of the
biggest pain points of vibe coding,
which is getting the app to actually
look good without writing a perfect
design prompt. So, if you have been
ignoring AI Studio Build, I think this
is a good time to try it again. Overall,
it's pretty cool. Anyway, let me know
your thoughts in the comments.
>> [music]
>> If you like this video, consider
donating through the super thanks option
or becoming a member by [music] clicking
the join button. Also, give this video a
thumbs up and subscribe to my channel.
I'll see you in the next one. Until
then, bye. [music]
>> [music]