[music]
>> Hi. Welcome to another video. So, this
video will be more of a comparison
video. And by comparison, I don't mean
that this is going to be a super
scientific benchmark breakdown where I
pull up 20 charts and pretend that one
number explains everything.
That is not really how AI coding tools
work anymore. The model matters, of
course. Benchmarks matter. Raw coding
ability matters, but the plan also
matters. The limits matter. The tooling
matters. The ecosystem matters. The way
you are allowed to use the model
matters. And honestly, the feeling of
whether you can code freely or whether
you're constantly watching your usage
meter matters a lot as well. So, in this
video, I want to talk about the four
coding subscriptions that I think are
the most interesting right now.
We have GLM coding plan.
We have Claude Code.
We have Codex. And we have Kimmy. These
four are not exactly the same kind of
product, but they are fighting for the
same type of user. They are all trying
to be the thing you pay for when you
want an AI coding workflow that can
actually help you build, refactor,
debug, review, and ship real projects.
And that is why this comparison is
interesting because if you are a casual
user, almost anything is fine. You can
use the free tier of one tool, the trial
of another tool, and just jump around.
But if you are someone who codes every
day, then the question becomes
different. It is not just which one is
the smartest.
It is which one gives me enough usage to
actually work.
Which one can handle front end and back
end. Which one is flexible enough to use
in the tools I already like. Which one
feels reliable when the code base gets
messy.
And which one is worth paying for every
month.
That is the real comparison. So, let's
start with GLM coding plan. GLM coding
plan is interesting because it gives you
access to GLM 5.1 and GLM 5.1 is a very
good model. It is strong at front end.
It is good at back end. It can reason
through a larger coding task without
instantly falling apart.
It can make decent UI decisions. It can
understand existing code. And it can
usually follow project structure better
than a lot of cheaper models.
It is not perfect, obviously. No coding
model is perfect, but GLM 5.1 feels like
one of those models that can actually
sit in the serious coding category
instead of the fun demo model category.
The thing that makes the GLM coding plan
different is not just the model, though.
It is the flexibility. You are not
locked into one official app. You can
use it with tools like Claude Code,
Kilocode, Cursor, OpenCode, Kline, and
other coding agents that support this
kind of provider setup. And that is a
huge deal. Because a lot of these coding
subscriptions are basically saying, "Pay
us every month, but only use the model
inside our own product." GLM is more
open than that. If you like Kilocode,
you can use it there.
If you like Claude Code's workflow, you
can route it there. If you want to test
it in another agent, you can do that as
well.
That alone makes the plan feel more
useful because it lets you choose the
workflow instead of forcing the workflow
on you.
I use it with Kilocode myself,
especially the Kilo CLI. The setup is
very easy. You run the connect command,
select GLM coding plan, enter your API
key, and then you can start using it.
That kind of setup is exactly what I
like because it does not make the
subscription feel trapped. Now, the big
downside is pricing. GLM increased the
pricing by a lot. The plan is now around
$18, $72, and $160 a month depending on
the tier you choose. The pricing does go
down
if you take a yearly or quarterly plan,
but still, it is more expensive than it
used to be. So, I don't want to pretend
that GLM is just this tiny cheap option
anymore. It is not.
It has moved closer to the serious paid
coding plan category.
But even with that,
the value can still be strong because
the flexibility is strong.
If you are only using one official app,
then maybe the pricing feels harder to
justify.
But if you are the kind of person who
jumps between Kilocode, Claude Code
style workflows, Cursor, Kline, and
other tools, GLM coding plan becomes
much more interesting.
It becomes less like paying for one app
and more like paying for a coding model
that can move with you.
That is the best argument for GLM. It
gives you GLM 5.1. And it lets you use
it in the places where you actually want
to code.
Next, let's talk about Claude Code.
Claude Code is still one of the most
important AI coding tools. I don't think
anyone can deny that.
It changed how a lot of people think
about terminal coding agents.
It made the workflow feel natural.
It gave people a way to talk to an agent
inside a repo and let it inspect files,
edit code, run commands, and iterate.
And the models are still very good.
When Claude is good, it is really good.
For front end work, Claude has often
felt stronger than GPT models.
It tends to understand design better.
It can produce nicer UI.
It can make cleaner visual choices.
And it usually has a better sense of
what a usable front end should look
like.
For back end work, it is also capable.
It can read code bases well.
It can reason about bugs.
And it can explain changes clearly.
So, the problem with Claude Code is not
that the product is bad.
The problem is the value equation.
The $20 plan can be useful,
but it is low if you are doing serious
daily coding. The $100 and $200 plans
are more serious, but those prices are
not easy to recommend anymore. And the
biggest issue is that you are mostly
tied to Claude Code itself. You are
paying for the Claude Code is still
premium, but it is premium in a way that
now feels harder to justify for a lot of
people. If you are an Anthropic power
user and you love Claude Code and you
can afford the higher plans, then sure,
it can still make sense.
But if you're asking me what I would
recommend to most people, I don't think
Claude Code is the automatic answer
anymore. It used to be easier to say,
"Just use Claude Code." Now, there are
too many strong alternatives. One of
those alternatives is Codex. Codex has
been getting better in a very noticeable
way. And what makes Codex interesting is
that it is not just one thing. You have
the local coding workflow.
You have the ChatGPT side.
You have the app experience.
You have cloud tasks. You have code
review features. You have the broader
OpenAI ecosystem around it. That makes
Codex feel like more of a complete
coding platform rather than just a
terminal tool. The pricing also makes it
interesting. Codex starts from the free
tier, which already gives people a way
to try it. Then the $20 plan gives you a
lot more room. And if you move to the
$100 or $200 plans, the limits become
much bigger. OpenAI also keeps improving
how the usage resets and how Codex fits
into the rest of the subscription. So,
for a lot of people, the $20 Codex
option is going to feel much more
reasonable than jumping straight into a
$100 or $200 dedicated coding
subscription. The model itself is really
good, too. Codex is strong at
understanding code bases. It is good at
refactors. It is good at explaining what
it is doing. It is good at long coding
sessions where you want it to keep track
of the project instead of treating every
prompt like a fresh one-off task. It is
also very good when you use it for back
end work, debugging, tests, scripts,
architecture, and general engineering
tasks.
The only real weakness I still see is
front end taste. Sometimes Codex can
make front end UIs that are technically
correct, but visually bland. It can
build the thing, but the design might
not feel as sharp as Claude or GLM. It
can overuse generic layouts, generic
spacing, generic cards, and generic
colors if you do not guide it properly.
But that weakness is fixable. If you use
good instructions, skills, design rules,
examples, or a strong front end
workflow, Codex improves a lot. That is
why I still rate Codex very highly.
Because the baseline engineering ability
is strong. The ecosystem is strong. The
limits are competitive. And the tool
keeps improving. If you already use
ChatGPT for research, writing, image
work, voice, planning, or general AI
tasks, Codex becomes even easier to
justify. You are not only paying for a
coding agent, you're paying for a
broader AI subscription where the coding
agent is part of the package. That is a
big advantage. Claude Code feels more
focused, but Codex feels more complete.
And for a lot of people,
complete is more useful than focused.
Now, let's talk about Kimmy. Kimmy is
the one I would describe as strong, but
more specific. The Kimmy plan gives you
access to Kimmy K2.6, and Kimmy good at
generating code. It can be good at
solving specific problems,
but the consistency is not always on the
same level. And when I'm paying for a
coding plan, consistency matters more
than occasional brilliance.
Because in real coding work, you do not
just need the model to be impressive
once. You need it to be reliable across
boring tasks. You need it to edit the
right files. You need it to follow
instructions. You need it to not
overcomplicate simple fixes. You need it
to write tests when tests matter.
You need it to understand when not to
touch unrelated code. You need it to be
stable for front end, back end,
debugging, refactoring, and product
work.
That is where Kimmy is good.
But I do not think it is the safest
first pick.
I would still keep an eye on it
because Kimmy models have been moving
fast.
But in this specific comparison, I would
put it behind Codex and GLM 5.1 for
everyday coding. So, if I had to
simplify the whole comparison, I would
say it like this.
Claude Code is still the premium classic
option.
It has a great workflow. It has strong
models. It has a lot of mind share.
But the price and limits make it harder
to recommend broadly.
Kimmy is the interesting challenger.
It is capable and worth testing.
It is capable and worth testing, but I
don't think it is the best main option
unless you specifically like the Kimmy
model behavior or the pricing works
perfectly for your use case.
GLM coding plan is the flexible option.
It gives you GLM 5.1, which is genuinely
strong, and it lets you use that model
across multiple coding tools. That
flexibility is the killer feature.
Codex is the most complete option. It
gives you strong coding ability, a
growing coding workflow, ChatGPT
integration, cloud work, review
features, and a broader AI ecosystem
around it.
That is why this is not just a model
comparison.
If we were only talking about raw front
end output, Claude might still win in a
lot of cases. If we were only talking
about using one model inside many coding
tools, GLM would be the obvious pick.
If we were only talking about the
biggest general AI bundle with serious
coding included, Codex would be the
obvious pick.
If we were only talking about a strong
alternative model to experiment with,
Kimmy would be very interesting. But
most people are not buying four
subscriptions. Most people want to know
where to put their money. And for that,
I would narrow the answer down to two.
CodeX and GLM-5.1.
CodeX is the one I would choose if you
want the full AI ecosystem around your
coding workflow.
It is good for people who already use
ChatGPT, want strong code base
understanding, want cloud tasks, want
review features, and want one
subscription that does more than just
coding. GLM-5.1 is the one I would
choose if you want flexibility and
strong model performance inside the
coding tools you already like.
It is good for people who use Kilocode,
Claude Code style workflows, Cursor,
Klein, or other agent tools, and want a
model they can carry across those
workflows. So, for me, Claude Code is
still good, and Kimi is still worth
watching. But if I had to recommend the
two best options right now, CodeX and
GLM-5.1 are the best options.
Overall, it's pretty cool. Anyway, let
me know your thoughts in the comments.
If you like this [music] video, consider
donating through the Super Thanks
option, or becoming a member by clicking
the join button. Also, give this video
[music] a thumbs up and subscribe to my
channel. I'll see you in the next one.
Until then, bye.
>> [bell]