[music]
>> Hi, welcome to another video. So, there
is a new local model trending on hugging
face right now and it has one of the
longest names I have seen in a while. It
is called Gemma 412B Agentic Fable 5
Compose.
Yes, that is the actual name.
But for this video, I'm just going to
call it Gemma. As I'm recording this,
the model is sitting near the top of the
hugging face trending list.
It has already crossed 6,000 downloads
and received around 200 likes within its
first couple of days. So, naturally I
thought I should try it and see whether
it is actually as good as the model card
makes it sound.
And the claims are quite interesting.
This is a fine-tuned version of Google's
Gemma 412B Instruct model and it is
specifically tuned for coding, terminal
work, tool use, reasoning, and
multi-step agentic tasks.
The creator describes it as a small
local coding and tool using agent that
can read the available information,
reason about it, use tools, make
changes, and then verify its own work.
Everything runs locally, so there is no
API cost. Your data can stay on your
machine and you can even use it offline
once the model is downloaded. It is also
released as a GGUF model under the
Apache 2.0 license, which makes it quite
easy to run through apps like llama.cpp,
Ollama, and LM Studio.
The headline benchmark claim is on Tau 2
bench telecom, which tests multi-step
tool use.
According to the model card, the
original Gemma 412B model scored around
15% across 20 tasks, while this
fine-tuned scored around 55% under the
same local test setup.
That is where the 3.5x part of the model
name comes from.
The creator claims that this fine-tuned
is roughly three and a half times better
than the base model on those technical
agentic tasks. Now, take that with a
grain of salt.
This was a small 20-task local
evaluation using Q8 versions of both
models
and the creator explicitly says that the
results are not directly comparable with
the official Tau 2 leaderboard.
It is useful as a relative comparison
with the base model, but it is not proof
that this little 12B model is suddenly
competing with frontier models. In fact,
the creator says that large frontier
models can score above 90% in the same
general benchmark area.
They also admit that this fine-tuned
scores a little below the base Gemma
model on MMLU Pro, which measures more
general knowledge. So, this is a
specialized model.
It is supposed to trade a little
general-purpose knowledge for better
coding and agentic behavior.
If you want a general chatbot, this may
not be the right model.
If you want a local coding model that
can attempt tool calls and
terminal-style workflows, that is where
it is meant to be interesting.
There are four main quantizations
available. The smallest Q3KM version is
around 5.7 GB.
The recommended Q4KM version is around
6.87 GB.
Q6K is around 9.11 GB.
And Q8 is around 11.8 GB.
I would start with Q4KM for most
machines.
It is the recommended sweet spot, and it
should give you a reasonable balance
between memory use, speed, and quality.
You can also add the recommended
sampling parameters.
Set the temperature to one, top P to
0.95,
top K to 64, and the repetition penalty
to 1.1.
That last setting is important because
the model creator says that missing
repetition penalties can cause broken
output or repeating strings such as
0000.
Once that is done, open your terminal in
the same folder and run Ollama create
Gemma for agentic-f model file. After
Ollama creates the model, run Ollama run
Gemma for agentic. And that's it. You
now have the model running locally
through Ollama. Because this uses a new
Gemma for architecture, I would also
make sure that Ollama is fully updated
before importing it.
The second option is LM Studio, and this
is probably the easier route if you
prefer a graphical interface. Install LM
Studio, download the GGUF file from
Hugging Face, and import it. You can do
that from the app or from the terminal
by running LMS import followed by the
path to the GGUF file. Then, load the
model in LM Studio and use the same
sampling settings. Temperature 1, top P
0.95, top K 64, and a repetition penalty
of 1.1. At this point, you can use the
model as a normal local chat model. If
you want to connect it to another
application, open the developer section
in LM Studio and start the local API
server. You can also do this from the
terminal by running LMS server start. LM
Studio exposes an OpenAI compatible
local API, so a lot of editors and
coding tools can connect to it without
needing a paid API key. For example, you
can connect it to Zed. If you're using
Ollama, make sure the Ollama app or
Ollama server is running. Open Zed, go
to the model selector, and Zed should
automatically discover the models
installed in Ollama. Select Gemma for
agentic, and you can use it through
Zed's agent panel or inline assistant.
If you're using LM Studio, start its API
server first. Then open the model
selector in Zed and choose the model
from the LM Studio provider.
>> One thing to remember is that Zed uses a
context length of 4,096 tokens by
default with Ollama.
You can increase that in Zed's language
model settings if your machine has
enough memory. Something like 8,122
tokens is a sensible starting point, and
you can go higher if the model stays
stable and your hardware can handle it.
So, the setup is not particularly
difficult. The harder question is
whether you should actually use this
model every day.
And honestly, based on my testing, I do
not think it is reliable enough to be a
daily driver right now.
It is quite a bit buggy. Sometimes it
works properly, follows the request, and
gives a surprisingly good answer. At
other times, it can produce strange
output, get stuck, repeat things, expose
special tool-related tokens, or simply
fail to complete the workflow in a
useful way. The model card says that
many of these problems come from the
client or sampler configuration rather
than the weights themselves. For
example, leaked tool call or channel
tokens can happen when the front end
does not properly understand Gemma 4's
native tool format, and that may be
true. But from a practical user's
perspective, the distinction only
matters so much. If a model needs
exactly the right runtime, chat
template, sampler settings, and tool
parser to behave normally, the overall
experience is still buggy. This becomes
especially noticeable when you try to
use it as an agent inside an editor. A
normal one-shot coding question is
fairly simple, but once the model has to
inspect multiple files, call tools, make
changes, read the result, and continue
for several steps, reliability matters
much more. That is where I saw the
biggest problem. I would not trust this
model to work through a large repository
or make important changes without
carefully watching everything it does.
However, I also do not want to dismiss
it completely because there are places
where it is genuinely quite good. For
one-shot chat tasks, focused coding
questions, small code generation
requests, explanations, refactoring a
function, or asking for a self-contained
solution, it can work well.
And when it works, there are moments
where it feels better than you would
expect from a 12B local model. It can
sometimes be more persistent than the
base model, and it occasionally handles
a technical prompt in a much more useful
way. So, I can see why people are
interested in it and why it is trending,
but the phrase here is when it works.
The good outputs can be quite good, but
the consistency is not there yet. For
daily agentic coding, I would still use
a more reliable model. For
experimentation, quick one-shot tasks,
or simply seeing how far a 12B local
model can go, this is definitely worth
trying.
The creator is also already talking
about a V3, so hopefully the next
version improves the stability and
reduces some of this flailing and broken
behavior.
This is an interesting local model with
an ambitious goal.
It is free, private, relatively small,
and sometimes surprisingly capable.
But, it is also quite buggy, and I would
not recommend relying on it for serious
daily work yet. So, give it a try
through Ollama or LM Studio, connected
to something like Zed, and test it on
your own tasks. Just keep your
expectations realistic, and double-check
everything it does. Overall, it's pretty
cool. Anyway, let me know your thoughts
in the comments. If you like this video,
consider donating through the Super
Thanks option, or becoming a member by
clicking the join button. Also, give
this video [music] a thumbs up and
subscribe to my channel. I'll see you in
the next one. Until then, bye.
>> [music]