Hi, welcome to another video. So, Hermes
Agent 0.16 is out and this one is called
the Surface release. And honestly, this
is a very fitting name because I already
talked about Hermes Agent Desktop in a
previous video. And in that video, the
main point was that Hermes finally
became much easier to see and
understand. But this release is bigger
than just there is a desktop app now.
This is about Hermes getting proper
surfaces, a native desktop app, a much
more complete web dashboard, better
setup, better model selection, better
remote gateway support, and a cleaner
skill system. So, let's get right into
it. First, the scale of this release is
pretty crazy. So, this is not a tiny
patch release. This is a pretty large
step for Hermes. Now, the headline
feature is obviously Hermes desktop. I
already showed the desktop app in
detail, so I'm not going to repeat the
whole walkthrough here. But the
important change in 0.16 is that the
desktop app is now part of the main
Hermes story. It is not just some
separate experiment.
It is a real native app for Mac OS,
Linux and Windows. You get a proper chat
window, streaming responses, a
searchable session list, session
archive, drag and drop files into chat
clipboard image paste, a command pallet,
and the model picker right in the status
bar. So if someone looked at Hermes
before and thought this is interesting,
but it feels too much like a terminal
tool, this release directly addresses
that and that matters a lot. Because a
good agent can have a ton of features,
but if the only way to understand those
features is by reading config files and
terminal logs, most people will never
use it properly. The desktop app changes
that. It makes sessions, models, skills,
profiles, messaging, cron, and sub aents
feel more visible. That is why this
release is called surface. Hermes
already had a lot of powerful internals.
Now those internals are getting real
userfacing surfaces. The next big part
is remote gateway support in the desktop
app. This is actually one of the most
important changes for Sirius users. The
desktop app does not have to run Hermes
locally. You can point it at a remote
Hermes gateway and sign in through OOTH
or with a username and password. So your
laptop can just be the guey while the
actual agent runs on a server, a home
lab machine, a hosted box or maybe a
teammates's machine. That is a very
practical setup because your API keys,
your compute, your long running tasks
and your gateway integrations may not
belong on your laptop. They may belong
on a machine that stays online. And now
the desktop app can connect to that.
They also added multi-profile sessions.
Each profile can point to its own remote
host. And you can run concurrent
sessions across profiles in one window.
So instead of Hermes being one local
agent tied to one local setup, it starts
to feel more like a control panel for
multiple agent environments. That is
quite powerful. Now the web dashboard
also got a major upgrade. Previously,
the dashboard was useful, but it was
still more like a place to view and
manage parts of Hermes. In this release,
it becomes much closer to a full admin
panel. You can configure the MCP catalog
with enable and disable toggles. You can
manage messaging channels. You can
manage credentials, web hooks, hook
creation, memory configuration, gateway
controls, and system settings. There is
also a system page with update checks
and debug sharing. And there is a
channels page for configuring gateway
messaging platforms from the browser. So
if you want to connect Hermes to
Telegram, Discord, Slack, or another
platform, the goal is that you can do
more of that visually instead of SSHing
into a server and editing YAML. That is
a big usability improvement. And again,
it matches the theme of the release.
Hermes is not just adding more hidden
power. It is making the power easier to
operate. The onboarding also got easier.
There is now quick setup through Nouse
portal. So firsttime setup has two
clearer paths. You can do quick setup,
sign in with Nouse portal, get a model
picker and start chatting quickly. Or
you can do the full setup if you're a
power user and want to configure
everything more carefully. They also
added Herm's portal as the human
readable command for the portal
onboarding flow. This is another one of
those changes that sounds small but is
actually important because the first 5
minutes of a tool matter a lot. If
someone installs an agent and
immediately gets stuck choosing
providers, credentials, models, tools,
and configuration paths, they may just
quit. Quick setup makes Hermes more
approachable. And I think that is the
right move. Now, the model picker also
improved a lot. It now has fuzzy search
across the desktop app, the web
dashboard, the TUI, and the CLI. So, if
you only remember part of a model name,
you can type a few letters and find it.
Multi-endpoint providers are grouped
more cleanly, too, so the list should be
less messy. The catalog refreshes hourly
instead of daily, which means new models
can show up much faster. And in this
release window, they added models like
Deepseek V4 Flash, Miniax M3 with 1
million context, QN3.7 Plus, and Gemini
3.5 Flash in the relevant pickers. I
like this a lot because Hermes is at its
best when it is not locked to one
provider. You can use a cheaper model
for simple tasks. You can use a stronger
cloud model when the job is harder. You
can use local models when privacy or
cost matters. And you can route all of
that from the same system. So improving
the model picker is not just a UI polish
thing. It directly affects how practical
Hermes is day-to-day. Another feature I
really like is /do. This lets you take
back the last end turns. So if you sent
the wrong prompt or the agent started
going in the wrong direction, you can
back up, edit the previous message and
resend. It works in the CLI, the 2E and
messaging platforms like Telegram and
Discord. That is super useful because
with agents, one bad prompt can waste a
lot of time and sometimes you do not
want to start a brand new session. You
just want to rewind a little bit and
steer the conversation correctly. So
slash undo is a practical quality of
life feature. They also improved
interface choice. You can now choose
whether Hermes chat opens the classic
CLI or the TUI by default. And the TUI
now has a single/model command and a
unified sessions overlay. So if you
prefer the terminal interface, this
release still has improvements for you.
It is not desktop only. The CLI TUI web
dashboard, desktop app, and messaging
surfaces are all getting more
consistent. Now let's talk about skills.
The default skill set has been trimmed.
Hermes removed redundant or dead skills
from the default bundle, moved heavier
niche skills to optional installs, and
added relevance gates. So, context
specific skills do not show up for users
who do not need them. In normal terms,
the default setup should be less noisy.
That matters because skills are
powerful, but too many irrelevant skills
can make the agent messier. It can
increase context, confuse selection, and
make the UI feel crowded. So, I like
this change. They are not just adding
more and more forever. They are also
pruning. There is also a new trusted
NVIDIA skills tab in the skills hub. So
NVIDIA skills now sit alongside open
AAI, Anthropic and Hugging Face as a
trusted skills source. That means CUDA
X, AIQ, Copt and other NVIDIA related
skills can be discovered and installed
through the same skills hub flow. That
is interesting especially for people
working with GPU optimization or NVIDIA
specific tooling. Messaging also got
better.
>> There is a more structured streaming
event protocol. Telegram gets draft
formatting parody. There are per
platform streaming defaults, dashboard
toggles, Discord voice channel
improvements, fue meeting invitation
handling, matrix command aliases,
bluebubbles group mention gating, and a
bunch of gateway reliability fixes. I'm
not going to pretend every viewer needs
every one of those integrations, but the
direction is important. Hermes is trying
to be available wherever work happens.
For some people that is the desktop app.
For some it is Slack or Discord. For
some it is Telegram. For some it is a
self-hosted dashboard. And for serious
automation that multi-urface approach is
more useful than a tool that only lives
inside one terminal window. Security and
reliability also got a meaningful pass.
They pinned a patched Starlet version
for CVE202648710.
They hardened SSRF checks. They stripped
certain SOP process credentials. They
improved file safety guards. They
restored approval in pseudo context in
execute code paths. And they added more
dangerous Docker patterns to the safety
layer. This part is not flashy, but it
matters. The more capable an agent
becomes, the more important the
guardrails become. If an agent can run
tools, talk to messaging platforms,
manage credentials, connect to gateways,
and operate remotely, then security
cannot be treated like an afterthought.
There are also a lot of bug fixes.
The release notes say 399 issues were
closed in this window for desktop
specifically.
They fixed things like new chats
vanishing on refresh, the stop button
not interrupting cued turns properly,
background session messages bleeding
into the active transcript, completion
menu navigation, escape dismissal, and
IME enter behavior. Those are exactly
the kinds of fixes that make an app feel
less fragile. Not everyone is a headline
feature, but together they matter. So my
overall take is pretty simple. Hermes
Agent 0.16 is one of the most important
Hermes releases so far. Not because it
adds one magical new agent feature, but
because it makes Hermes easier to
access, easier to manage, and easier to
explain. The desktop app gives normal
users a real interface. The web
dashboard becomes a real admin panel.
Remote gateway support makes it useful
for server-based and team style setups.
Quick setup makes onboarding less
annoying. The fuzzy model picker makes
provider flexibility more usable. Slash
undo makes mistakes less painful. The
skill cleanup reduces noise and the
security and bug fix work makes the
whole thing feel more serious. It is
still not a basic chatbot and if you
only want a simple AI coding assistant,
Hermes may still be overkill. But if you
care about open source agents, local and
remote workflows, model routing, skills,
messaging platforms, scheduled jobs, and
multi-agent work, this release is very
interesting for me. The biggest thing is
that Hermes is becoming less hidden. The
power was already there. Now it is
getting surfaced in ways normal people
can actually use and that is exactly
what an agent platform needs. Overall,
it's pretty cool. Anyway, let me know
your thoughts in the comments. If you
like this video, consider donating
through the super thanks option or
becoming a member by clicking the join
button. Also, give this video a thumbs
up and subscribe to my channel. I'll see
you in the next one. Until then, bye.